as part of MIT course six as $0.99
作为麻省理工学院课程的一部分， 六分为 0.99美元
artificial general intelligence I've
人工智能我已经
gotten the chance to sit down with max
得到坐下来 ， 最大的机会
tegmark he is a professor here at MIT is
tegmark 他是 麻省理工学院 在这里 的教授 是
a physicist spent a large part of his
物理学家花了很大一部分 他的
career studying the mysteries of our
职业研究我们的奥秘
cosmological universe but he's also
宇宙宇宙， 但他也是
studied and delved into the beneficial
研究和深入研究有益的
possibilities and the existential risks
可能性和存在风险
of artificial intelligence amongst many
很多人工智能
other things he's the co-founder of the
其他事情他是联合创始人
future of life Institute author of two
未来生活学院的两位作者
books both of which I highly recommend
这两本书我都强烈 推荐
first our Mathematica universe
首先是我们的 Mathematica宇宙
second is life 3.0 he's truly an
第二是生命3.0， 他是真正的
out-of-the-box thinker and fun
开箱即用的思想家和乐趣
personality so I really enjoyed talking
个性所以我真的很喜欢说话
to him if you would like to see more of
如果你想 看到更多，请告诉他
these videos in the future please
请 将来播放这些视频
subscribe and also click the little bell
订阅并点击小铃铛
icon to make sure you don't miss any
图标，以确保您不会错过任何
videos also Twitter linked in AGI that
视频也是在 AGI 链接的Twitter
MIT that I do if you want to watch other
麻省理工学院，如果你想看别人，我会这样做
lectures or conversations like this one
讲座或对话这样一个
better yet go read Max's book life 3.0
更好的是阅读Max的书籍 生活3.0
chapter 7 on goals is my favorite it's
关于目标的第7章是我最喜欢的
really where philosophy and engineer and
真正的哲学和工程师和
come together and it opens with a quote
走到一起，打开报价
by dusty s key the mystery of human
通过尘土飞扬的关键人类的奥秘
existence lies not and just stayin alive
存在不在于，只是活着
but in finding something to live for
但在寻找生活的东西
lastly I believe that every failure
最后我认为 ， 每一次的失败
rewards us with an opportunity to learn
奖励我们 学习 的机会
in that sense I've been very fortunate
从那个意义上讲，我一直非常幸运
to fail in so many new and exciting ways
以 这么多新的 令人兴奋的方式 失败
and this conversation was no different
这次谈话 也不例外
I've learned about something called
我已经了解了 一些 叫做的 东西
radio frequency interference or RFI look
射频干扰或RFI外观
it up
它
apparently music and conversations from
显然是音乐和对话
local radio stations can bleed into the
当地广播电台可以流入
audio that you're recording in such a
那你在这样的记录音频
way that almost completely ruins that
几乎完全破坏了那种方式
audio it's an exceptionally difficult
音频这是一个非常困难的
sound source to remove so I've gotten
要删除的声源我已经得到了
the opportunity to learn how to avoid
有机会学习 如何 避免
RFI in the future during recording
录制期间将来的RFI
sessions of also gotten the opportunity
会议也 抓住了机会
to learn how to use Adobe Audition
学习 如何 使用Adobe Audition
and isotope rx6 to do some noise some
和同位素RX6做一些噪音 有一定的
audio repair
音频修复
of course this is exceptionally
当然这是特别的
difficult noise to remove I am an
难以消除的噪音我是一个
engineer I'm not an audio engineer
工程师我不是音频工程师
neither is anybody else in our group but
也不是任何 人在我们组 ，但
we did our best
我们 做到了 最好
nevertheless I thank you for your
不过我谢谢你
patience and I hope you're still able to
耐心，我希望你仍然能够
enjoy this conversation do you think
你觉得这个对话很享受吗？
there's intelligent life out there in
那里有聪明的生活
the universe
宇宙
let's open up with an easy question I
让我们打开一个简单的问题 我
have a lien minority of you here
在这里有你的少数留置权
actually when I give public lectures
实际上我在公开讲座的时候
Alfred asked for show of hands who
阿尔弗雷德要求举手示威
thinks there's intelligent life out
认为有智能生命 进行
there somewhere else and almost everyone
在其他地方，几乎每个人
put their hands up and when I ask why
举起手来，当我问为什么
they'll be like oh there's so many
他们会像哦那么多
galaxies out there there's gonna be but
那里的星系会有。但是
I'm a numbers nerd right so when you
我是一个数字书呆子，所以当你
look more carefully at it it's not so
仔细看看它 并非如此
clear at all if we when we talk about
如果我们谈论的话，那就完全清楚了
our universe first of all we don't mean
我们的宇宙首先我们不是故意的
all of space did we actually mean I
所有空间我们实际上 是指我
don't you can throw me in the universe
难道你不能把我扔进 宇宙中
if she wants behind you there it's we
如果她想要在你身后那就是我们
simply mean the spherical region of
简单地说是球形区域
space from which light has a time to
光有时间的空间
reach us so far during the fourteen
到目前为止，在十四岁时到达我们
point eight billion year 13.8 billion
点80亿年138亿
years since our Big Bang there's more
自从我们的大爆炸以来， 还有更多
space here but this is what we call a
这里的空间，但这就是我们所说的
universe because that's all we have
宇宙，因为这就是我们拥有的一切
access to mm-hmm so is there intelligent
访问 毫米-HMM所以是有智能
life here that's gotten to the point of
这里的生活已经达到了极致
building telescopes and computers my
建造望远镜和计算机 我的
guess is no actually no the probability
猜测实际上并不是概率
of it happening on any given planet is
在任何给定的星球上发生的事情都是
some number we don't know what it is and
一些我们不知道它是什么 和
what we do know is that the number can't
我们所知道的是 数字不能
be super-high because there's over a
超高，因为有超过
billion earth-like planets in the Milky
在银河系中有十亿个类似地球的行星
Way galaxy alone many of which are
单纯的方式银河 很多都是
billions of years older than Earth and
比地球和地球年长数十亿年
aside from some UFO believers in other
除了其他一些不明飞行物的信徒
reason is much evidence that any super
理由是任何超级的 证据
20 civilization has come here at all and
20 文明来到这里
so that's the famous Fermi paradox right
这就是着名的费米悖论吧
and then if you if you work the numbers
然后，如果你工作数字
what you find is that if you have no
你发现的是，如果你没有
clue what the probability is of getting
知道是什么的概率是 获得的
life on a given planet
在给定星球上的生活
could be 10 to the minus 10 and the
可能是10到10和10
minus 20 or 10 minus to any power tensor
减去20或10减去 任何功率 张量
equally likely if you want to be really
同样可能，如果你想真的
open-minded that translates into it
思想开放， 转化为它
being equally likely that our nearest
同样可能是我们最近的
neighbor is 10 to the 16 meters away 10
邻居距离10到16米10
to the 17 meters away 10 to the 18 now
到17米外10到18 现在
by the time he gets much less than than
的时候，他变得比远远低于
10 to the 16 already we pretty much know
我们已经非常了解 10到16
there is nothing else that's close and
没有别的东西可以接近了
when you get the other would have
当你得到其它的就 没有
discovered us they yeah they would have
发现了我们他们会有的
been discovered as long or if they're
被发现一样 长或者如果他们
really close we would have probably know
真的很接近我们可能知道的
that some engineering projects that
那个工程项目那个
they're doing and if it's beyond 10 to
他们正在做，如果它超过 10到
the 26 meters that's already outside of
26米已经在外了
here so my guess is actually that there
所以我的 猜测实际上就是那里
are we are the only life in here they've
我们是他们 唯一的生活 吗？
gotten the point of building advanced
得到了先进的建设点
tech which i think is very um puts a lot
我觉得 非常 有用的技术
of responsibility on our shoulders not
肩负责任不是
screw up you know I think people who
搞砸了，你知道，我认为 人 谁
take for granted that it's okay for us
理所当然地认为这对我们没问题
to screw up have an accident in a
搞砸了具有在发生事故
nuclear war or go extinct somehow
核战争或以某种方式灭绝
because there's a star trek-like
因为有一个星际迷航
situation out there with some other life
与其他生活有关的情况
forms are gonna come and bail us out and
表格会来，并保释我们
doesn't matters what I think they're
我觉得 他们 不重要
lulling us into a false sense of
哄骗我们进入一种虚假的安全感
security I think it's much more prudent
安全我认为这更加谨慎
to say you know let's be really grateful
说你知道 让我们真的很感激
for this amazing opportunity we've had
为了 这个 我们所拥有的惊人机会
and make the best of it just in case it
并做出最好的以防万一 它
is down to us so from a physics
下降 到 了 我们这么从物理学
perspective do you think intelligent
透视你认为聪明 吗 ？
life so it's unique from a sort of
生活所以它是独一无二的
statistical view of the size of the
的大小的统计视图
universe but from the basic matter of
宇宙，但从基本的问题
the universe how difficult is it for
宇宙有多难
intelligent life to come about the kind
智能生活来的那种
of advanced tech building life I in is
我所在的先进科技建筑生活
implied in your statement that is really
在你的陈述中暗示的是真的
difficult to create something like a
难以创造 像
human species well I think I think what
人类物种我认为我认为是什么
we know is that going from no life to
我们知道， 从没有生命 走向
having life that can do ARCA a level of
拥有可以做到ARCA水平的生活
tech there's some sort of - going beyond
科技有某种 - 超越
that than actually settling our whole
而不是实际解决我们的整体
universe with life there is some road
宇宙与生命有一些 道路
major roadblock there which is
那里的主要障碍是
great filter as that's sometimes called
很棒的过滤器， 有时 被称为
which which tough to get through it's
哪个难以通过它
either that roadblock is either beef
这个路障要么是 牛肉
behind us or in front of us I'm hoping
在我们身后或在我们面前，我希望
very much that it's behind us I'm super
很多，它在 我们 身后， 我是超级的
excited every time we get a new report
我们每次收到新报告都很兴奋
from NASA saying they failed to find any
来自美国国家航空航天局说他们找不到任何东
life on Mars
生命在火星上
like just awesome because that suggests
就像真棒一样， 因为这表明
that the hard part maybe what maybe he
那个 困难的部分 可能 就是 他
was getting the first ribosome or or
得到第一个 核糖体或或
some some very low-level kind of
一些非常低级 的
stepping stone so they were home free
踏脚石， 所以他们在家里免费
cuz if that's true then the future is
如果那是 真的，那么未来就是
really only limited by our own
真的只 受我们自己的限制
imagination it'd be much luckier if it
如果它想象它会更幸运
turns out that this level of life is
事实证明， 生活水平如此
kind of a dime a dozen but maybe there
一打一打，但可能在那里
is some other problem like as soon as a
是 一个其他问题，如一个
civilization gets advanced technology
文明获得先进技术
within a hundred years they get into
他们进入 了一百年之 内
some stupid fight with themselves and
与自己和自己的一些愚蠢的斗争
poof yeah no that would be a bummer
噗， 是的 ，这不会是一个无赖
yeah so you've explored the mysteries of
是的， 所以你已经探索了它的奥秘
the universe the cosmological universe
宇宙是宇宙宇宙
the one that's sitting between us today
我们今天坐在我们之间的人
I think you've also begun to explore the
我想你也开始 探索 了
other universe which is sort of the
其他宇宙就是 那种
mystery the mysterious universe of the
神秘的 宇宙 之谜
mind of intelligence of intelligent life
智慧生活的智慧
so is there a common thread between your
所以你们之间有一个共同点
interest or in the way you think about
兴趣或你想的方式
space and intelligence oh yeah when I
太空和智慧 哦，是的， 当我
was a teenager yeah I was already very
是一个十几岁的孩子， 我已经非常
fascinated by the biggest questions and
着迷于最大的问题和
I felt that the two biggest quite
我觉得两个最大的相当
mysteries of all in science where our
在我们的科学中所有的奥秘
universe out there and our universe in
宇宙在那里 和我们的宇宙在
here yeah so it's quite natural after
在这里， 所以 这是很自然的
having spent a quarter of a century on
花了四分之一个世纪
my career thinking a lot about this one
我的职业生涯思考 了很多关于 这一个
I'm now indulging in the luxury of doing
我现在正沉迷于做事的奢侈
research on this one it's just so cool I
研究 这个 我 真的很酷
feel the time is right now for you
觉的时间 ，现在你
Trane's greatly deepening our
特灵大大加深了我们的工作
understanding of this just start
对此的理解才刚刚 开始
exploring this one yeah because I think
探索这一个是的，因为我认为
I think a lot of people view
我想 很多 人都认为
intelligence as something mysterious
智慧是一种神秘的东西
that can only exist and biological
只能 存在和生物
organisms like us and therefore dismiss
像我们这样的生物，因此解散
all talk about artificial general
都谈人工将军
intelligence is science fiction
情报是科幻小说
but from my perspective as a physicist
但是从 我 作为一个物理学家的角度
you know I am a blob of quarks and
你 知道我是一团夸克和
electrons moving around in a certain
电子在某种程度上四处移动
pattern and processing information in
模式和处理信息
certain ways and this is also a blob of
某些方式， 这 也是一个小点
quarks and electrons
夸克和电子
I am NOT smarter than the water bottle
我 不比水瓶 更聪明
because I'm made of different kind of
因为我是由不同的人组成的
works I'm made of up quarks and down
工作我是由夸克和下来组成的
quarks exact same kind as this it's a
夸克与它完全相同
there's no secret sauce I think in me
我觉得在我身上没有秘密的味道
it's all about the pattern of the
这完全是关于模式 的
information processing and this means
信息处理和这意味着
that there's no law of physics saying
没有 物理定律 说
the way that we can't create technology
我们无法创造技术的方式
which can have helped us by being
这可以帮助我们
incredibly intelligent and helped us
非常聪明， 帮助了我们
crack mysteries that we couldn't in
我们无法解开的谜团
other words I think we really only seen
换句话说我认为我们 真的只见过
the tip of the intelligence iceberg so
智力冰山的一角如此
far yeah so the perceptron ium yeah so
远啊所以感知 IUM 呀等等
you can't go in this amazing term it's a
你不能进入这个令人惊讶的术语它是一个
hypothetical state of matter sort of
物质的假设状态排序
thinking from a physics perspective what
从物理学角度思考什么
is the kind of matter that can help as
是物质的种类 ，可以 作为 帮助
you're saying a subjective experience
你说的是一种主观体验
emerged consciousness emerge so how do
出现意识出现了怎么办
you think about consciousness from this
你从这里思考意识
physics perspective very good question
物理学观点非常 好的问题
so again I think many people have
所以， 我 再次 想 很多人都有
underestimated our ability to make
低估我们 的 能力 做
progress on this and by convincing
这方面的进展和说服力
themselves it's hopeless because somehow
他们自己 因为某种原因而 无望
we're missing some ingredient that we
我们错过了一些我们的成分
need or some new consciousness particle
需要或一些新的意识粒子
or whatever I happen to think that we're
或者无论我碰巧认为 我们是什么
not missing anything and and that it's
没有遗漏任何东西 ，而且确实如此
or not the interesting thing about
或者不是 有趣的事情
consciousness that gives us this amazing
让我们感到惊奇的意识
subjective experience of colors and
色彩和主观的主观体验
sounds and emotions and so on is rather
相反，声音和情绪等等
something at the higher level about the
关于这个问题的更高层次的事情
patterns of information processing
信息 处理模式
that's why that's why I am like to think
这就是为什么我喜欢思考的原因
about this idea of perceptron Neum what
关于 感知器Neum的 这个想法 是 什么
does it mean for an arbitrary physical
这是否意味着任意的身体
system to be conscious in terms of what
系统要有意识到什么
its particles are doing or its
它的颗粒正在做或 它的
information is doing I don't think I
信息正在做我不认为我
don't hate carbon chauvinism you know
不要讨厌你知道的碳沙文主义
this attitude you have to be made of
你必须要有这种态度
carbon atoms to be smart or conscious
碳原子要聪明或有意识
something about the information
关于信息的一些事情
processing yes kind of matter performs
处理是的事情执行
yeah and you know yeah I have my
是的你知道 我有我的
favorite equations here describing
这里最喜欢的方程式
various fundamental aspects of the world
世界各种基本方面
I feel that I think one day maybe
我觉得 有 一天 我想
someone who's watching this will come up
有人谁在看这将拿出
with the equations that information
用方程表那些信息
processing has to satisfy to be
处理必须满足
conscious I'm quite convinced there is
有意识的 ，我很相信有
big discovery to be made there yeah
要做的重大发现是的
because let's face it sumit we know that
因为我们知道这一点，让我们面对它
some information processing is conscious
一些信息处理是有意识的
because we are yeah conscious but we
因为我们是有意识的，但我们
also know that a lot of information
也知道很多信息
processing is not conscious like most of
加工并不像大多数人那样有意识
the information processing happening in
信息处理发生在
your brain right now is not conscious
你的大脑现在没有 意识
there is like 10 megabytes per second
每秒大约 有 10兆字节
coming in and even just through your
进来的 ，甚至只是通过你的
visual system you are not conscious
你 没有意识到的视觉系统
about your heartbeat regulation or or
关于你的心跳调节或或
most things by even even like if I just
大多数事情 甚至就像我 只是
ask you to like read what it says here
请 你 仔细阅读这里所说的内容
you look at it and then oh now you know
你看着它然后哦，现在你知道了
what it said but you don't aware of how
它说了但是你不 知道怎么 做
the computation actually happened you're
计算实际上发生了你
like the your consciousness is like the
就像你的意识就像
CEO that got an email at the end we
最后收到电子邮件的 CEO 我们
leave with a final answer so what is it
留下最后的答案，那是什么呢
that makes the difference I think that's
这让 我 有所不同
a both of us great science mystery we're
一个我们两个伟大的科学之谜 我们
actually starting it a little bit in my
实际上在我的开始一点点
lab here at MIT but I also I think it's
麻省理工学院的实验室，但 我也认为是
just a really urgent question the answer
这是一个非常紧迫的问题
for started I mean if you're an
开始我的意思是， 如果你是一个
emergency room doctor and you have an
急诊室医生，你有一个
unresponsive patient coming in and
反应迟钝的患者在未来和
wouldn't it be great if in addition to
如果除此之外不会很好
having a CT scan
进行CT扫描
you had a consciousness scanner mm-hmm
你有一个意识扫描仪mm-hmm
that could figure out whether this
这可以弄清楚是否这样
person is actually having locked-in
这个人 实际上已经锁定了
syndrome or is actually comatose and in
综合症或实际上是昏迷的
the future imagine if we build the
未来的想象，如果我们建立
robots or the machine that we can have
机器人或我们可以拥有的机器
really good conversations which I think
我 认为真的很好的 对话
it's mostly very likely to happen right
它 很 可能是正确发生的
wouldn't you want to know like if your
难道你不想知道，如果你的
home helped a robot is actually
家帮了一个机器人
experiencing anything or just like a
经历任何事情或只是像
zombie I mean would you prefer what
僵尸我的意思是你更喜欢什么
would you prefer would you prefer that
你愿意更喜欢吗？
it's actually unconscious so that you
它实际上是无意识的，所以你
don't have to feel guilty about
不必感到内疚
switching it off or giving me boring
把它关掉或给我无聊
chores or would you prefer
家务活或者你更喜欢
well the certainly would we would prefer
那么我们肯定会更喜欢
I would prefer the appearance of
我更喜欢外观
consciousness
意识
but the question is whether the
但问题是， 是否
appearance of consciousness is different
意识的出现是不同的
than cost consciousness itself and sort
比成本意识本身和排序
of ask that as a question yeah do you
抚 ，作为一个问题 啊你
think we need to you know understand
认为我们需要你了解
what consciousness is solve the hard
什么意识解决了困难
problem of consciousness in order to
为了意识问题
build something like an a GI system no I
建立类似 的 地理标志系统中 没有我
don't think that and I think we we will
不要这么想，我想我们 会的
probably be able to build things even if
即使 是，也许 能够 建造东西
we don't answer that question but if we
我们不回答这个 问题， 但如果我们
want to make sure that what happens is a
要确保 发生的事情是一个
good thing we better solve it first so
好的， 我们最好先解决它
it's a wonderful controversy you're
这是一个很好的争议你
raising there there where you have
在那里举起你所拥有的地方
basically three points of view about the
基本上有三种观点
heart problem sir there are two
心脏问题先生有两个
different points of view that both
两者的不同观点
conclude that the hard problem of
得出结论，这是一个难题
consciousness is BS you're on one hand
意识是BS，你一方面
you have some people like Daniel Dennett
你有 像Daniel Dennett这样的人
who say this is our consciousness is
谁说这是我们的 意识
just BS because consciousness is the
只是因为知觉是 BS
same thing as intelligence there's no
与情报一样的事情就是没有
difference so anything which acts
所以 任何 行为的差异
conscious is conscious just like like we
意识就像我们一样有意识
are and then there are also a lot of
是，然后还有很多
people including many top AI researchers
人们包括许多顶级AI研究人员
I know you say all conscience is just
我知道你说所有的 良心都是公正的
because of course machines
废话， 因为当然机器
should never be conscious tonight
今晚永远不应该有意识
they're always gonna is gonna be zombies
他们总是会成为僵尸
never have to feel guilty about how you
永远不必对 你如何 感到 内疚
treat them and then there's a third
对待他们，然后是第三个
group of people including Giulio Tononi
一群人，包括Giulio Tononi
for example and and another just of
例如和另一个
chakana brothers
查卡纳兄弟
I would put myself Falls on this middle
我会把自己倒 在这个中间
camp who say that actually some
阵营谁说实际上 有些
information processing is conscious and
信息处理是有意识 和
in some is not so let's find the
在一些不那么让我们找到
equation which can be used to determine
方程可以被用于确定
which it is and I think we've just been
这是我认为我们刚刚
a little bit lazy kind of running away
有点懒样逃跑
from this problem for a long time it's
从 这个 问题很 长一段时间 了
been almost taboo would even mention the
已经快忌讳 甚至 会 提
c-word a lot of circles because look but
c-word很多圈子因为看起来但是
we should stop making excuses this is a
我们应该停止找借口这 是一个
science question and we can the rock
科学问题，我们 可以摇滚
there are ways we can even test test any
有些方法我们 甚至可以测试任何测试
theory that makes predictions for this
理论使预言此
and coming back to this helper robot I
并回到 这个辅助机器人我
mean so you said you'd want to help a
意思是所以你说你想 帮助 一个
robot to certainly act conscious and
机器人肯定会有意识地行动
treat you like to have conversations
对待你喜欢谈话
with us I think so wouldn't you would
和 我们一起， 我想你 也不会
you feel would you feel a little bit
你觉得你会有点感觉
creeped out if you realize that it was
如果你意识到它是悄悄的
just glossed up the tape recorder they
他们把录音机搞砸了
know there was just Sambi and there's
知道只有Sambi而且那里
some faking emotion would you prefer
你更喜欢 一些假装情绪
that it actually had an experience or
它实际上有经验 或
will you prefer that it's actually not
你会不会喜欢它实际上不是
experiencing anything so you feel you
体验任何让你感觉到的东西
don't have to feel guilty about what you
你不必为自己感到内疚
do to it it's such a difficult question
做到这一点是一个如此困难的问题
because you know it's like when you're
因为你知道它就像你的时候一样
in a relationship and you say well I
在一段感情中，你说得好
love you and the other person I love you
爱你和我 爱你的另一个人
back it's like asking well do they
回来就像问他们好
really love you back or are they just
真的爱你回来或他们 只是
saying they love you back
说他们爱你了
do you don't you really want them to
你不要你真的希望他们
actually love you I it's hard to it's
实际上爱你， 我 很难
hard to really know the difference
很难真正了解 其中的差异
between everything seeming like there's
在所有看似有的东西之间
consciousness present there's
意识存在于那里
intelligence present there's affection
情报呈现出那种感情
passion love and and actually being
激情的爱和实际存在
there I'm not sure do you have a
那里我不确定你有没有
question let's just like to make it a
问题让我们想成为一个问题
bit more pointed so Mass General
更有针对性的群众将军
Hospital is right across the river right
医院就在河对面
yes suppose suppose you're going in for
是的， 假设你想参加
a medical procedure and they're like you
一个医疗程序 ，他们就像你一样
know
知道
furnish the agent what we're gonna do is
为代理商提供我们将要做的事情
we're gonna give you a muscle relaxant
我们会给你肌肉松弛剂
so you won't be able to move and you're
所以你将无法 移动而且你是
gonna feel excruciating pain during the
在 这 期间会感到难以忍受的痛苦
whole surgery but you won't be able to
整个手术，但你不能
do anything about it but then we're
做任何事情 ， 但我们就是
gonna give you this drug that erases
会给你这种消失的药物
your memory of it would you be cool
你 对它的 记忆 ，你会 很酷
about that no what
关于 那没有什么
difference that you're conscious about
你 意识到的差异
it or not if there's no behavioral
它或 没有，如果没有行为
change right right that's a really
改变正确，这 是真的
that's a really clear way to put it
这是一个非常明确的方式
that's yeah it feels like in that sense
那是感觉就像 在 那个意义上
experiencing it is a valuable quality so
体验它是一种有价值的品质
actually being able to have subjective
实际上能够有主观性
experiences at least in that cases is
至少在 这种情况下的经历是
valuable and I think we humans have a
有价值的，我认为我们人类有一个
little bit of a bad track record also of
一个坏磁道记录的点点也
making these self-serving arguments that
提出这些自私自利的论点
other entities aren't conscious you know
其他实体没有意识到你知道
people often say oh these animals can't
人们经常说哦这些动物不能
feel pain right it's okay to boil
感觉疼痛， 可以煮沸
lobsters because we asked them if it
龙虾，因为我们问他们是否
hurt and they didn't say anything and
受伤了，他们没有说什么
now there was just the paper out saying
现在只有纸张说出来了
lobsters did do feel pain when you boil
当你煮沸时，龙虾确实感到疼痛
them and they're banning it in
他们和他们在禁止它
Switzerland it and and we did this with
瑞士它和我们这样做 了
slaves too often and say oh they don't
奴隶经常说，哦，他们没有
mind they don't maybe or aren't
介意他们 可能 不会 或不会
conscious or women don't have souls or
有意识的或女人没有灵魂或
whatever I'm a little bit nervous when I
无论我是有点紧张，当我
hear people just take as an axiom that
听到人们只是把它 当作一个公理
machines can't have experience ever I
机器不能有经验 我
think this is just this really
认为这只是 这真的
fascinating science question is what it
令人着迷的科学问题是它
is
是
let's research it and try to figure out
让我们研究它并试图找出答案
what it is it makes the difference
是什么让它与众不同
between
之间
unconscious intelligent behavior and
无意识的智能行为和
conscious intelligent behavior so in
有意识的智能行为，使
terms of so if you think of a Boston
如果你想到一个波士顿的话
Dynamics human robot being sort of with
动力学人类 机器人与...
a broom being pushed around the its
一把扫帚被推到 它周围
starts it starts pushing on his
开始它开始推他的
consciousness question so let me ask do
意识问题所以让 我问一下
you think an AGI system like a few
你认为AGI系统就像少数几个
neuroscientists believe needs to have a
神经科学家认为需要有一个
physical embodiment needs to have a body
物理实施方式需要有一个身体
or something like a body no I don't
或者像身体这样的东西， 不，我没有
think so you mean to have to have a
我想 你必须要有一个
conscious experience to have
有意识的经历
consciousness I do think it helps a lot
意识我认为它 有很大帮助
to have a physical embodiment learn the
有 一个物理 实施例 的学习
kind of things about the world that
关于这个世界的事情
they're important to us humans for sure
它们 肯定 对 我们人类 很重要
but I don't think
但我不认为
bah diamond is necessary after you've
你 需要bah钻石
learned it just have the experience
得知它只是有经验
think about when you're dreaming right
想想你什么时候做梦吧
your eyes are closed you're not getting
你的眼睛闭着， 你没有得到
any sensory input you're not behaving or
你没有表现出来的任何感官输入
moving in any way but there's still an
以任何方式移动，但仍有一个
experience there right and so there's
在那里体验，所以 有
clearly the experience that you have
显然你拥有的经验
when you see something tool in your
当你看到你的工具
dreams isn't coming from your eyes it's
梦想不是来自你的眼睛
just the information processing itself
只是信息处理本身
in your brain which is that experience
在你的大脑里面就是那种体验
right but if I put another way I'll say
对，但如果我换另一种方式，我会说
because it comes from neuroscience is
因为它来自神经科学是一
the reason you want to have a body and a
原因你希望 有一个身体 和
physical something like a physical like
物理上像物理的东西
a you know a physical system is because
你知道一个物理 系统 是因为
you want to be able to preserve
你希望能够保存
something in order to have a self you
为了拥有自己的东西你
could argue would you you need to have
可以说你会， 你需要 有
some kind of embodiment of self to want
某种想要自我 的体现
to preserve well now we're getting a
保持良好现在我们得到了一个
little bit on Drop amorphic that's inter
关于Drop amformaic的一点点
and super more fising things miss Mamie
Mamie想念的东西太多了
tossing like self-preservation instincts
像自我保护的本能一样折腾
I mean we are evolved organisms right
我的意思是我们是正确的进化生物
right so Darwinian evolution endowed us
正确的达尔文进化论赋予了我们
and other involve all organism with the
和其他涉及所有有机体
self-preservation instinct as those that
那些自我保护的本能
didn't have those self-preservation
没有那些 自我保护
genes are clean out of the gene pool
基因是干净了 基因库
right right but if you build an
是的，但如果你建立一个
artificial general intelligence the mind
强人工智能头脑
space that you can design is much much
你可以设计的空间非常多
larger than just a specific subset of
不是 的只是一个特定子集大
minds that can evolve that happen so
可以发展的思想
they CERN a GI mind doesn't necessarily
他们CERN的GI心灵 并不一定
have to have any self-preservation
必须 有任何自我保护
instinct it also doesn't necessarily
本能它也不一定
have to be so individualistic as I'd
要这么个人主义为 我最好
like imagine if you could just first of
想象一下， 如果你可以只是第一个
all it or we're also very afraid of
所有它或我们也非常害怕
death you know I suppose you could back
死， 你知道我想你可以回来
yourself up every five minutes and then
然后每五分钟自己动手一次
your airplane is about to crash you like
你的飞机即将 崩溃
shucks I'm just counted I'm gonna lose
糟透了我才算我会输
the last five minutes of experiences
最后五分钟的经历
it's my last cloud backup you're dying
这是我的最后一次云备份，你正在 死去
you know it's not this big a deal or if
你知道这不是 这么 大 的 交易，或者
we could just copy experiences between
我们可以复制之间的经验
our minds easily like me which we could
我们的思想很容易就像我一样
easily do if we were silicon based right
如果我们是基于硅的，那就很容易做到
then
然后
maybe we would feel a little bit more
也许我们会觉得有点 多
like a hive mind actually but maybe is
实际上就像一个蜂巢的头脑， 但 也许 是
he so so there's a so I don't think we
他是如此，所以我不 认为我们
should take for granted at all that AG I
应该理所当然地认为 AG I
will have to have any of those sort of
必须有这样的任何一种
competitive as alpha male instincts
具有竞争力的阿尔法雄性本能
right on the other hand you know this is
有权 在 另一方面，你知道这是
really interesting because I think some
非常有趣，因为我觉得有些
people go too far and say oh of course
人们走得太远，当然可以说哦
we don't have to have any concerns
我们没有 任何顾虑
either that advanced AI will have those
要么高级AI会有那些
instincts because we can build anything
本能，因为我们可以建立任何东西
you want that there's there's a very
你想要 那里有一个非常的
nice set of arguments going back to
很好的一组参数可以追溯到
Steve Omohundro and Nick Bostrom and
Steve Omohundro和Nick Bostrom以及
others just pointing out that when we
其他人只是指出 我们的时候
build machines we normally build them
构建 我们通常构建它们的机器
with some kind of goal you know win this
以某种目标，你知道赢得这个
chess game drive this car safely or
国际象棋游戏安全 或 驾驶这辆车
whatever and as soon as you put in a
什么，一旦你投入
goal into machine especially if it's
进入机器的目标， 特别是 如果它
kind of open-ended goal and the machine
一种开放式的目标和机器
is very intelligent it'll break that
非常聪明，它会破坏它
down into a bunch of sub goals and one
分成一堆子目标和一个
of those gold will almost always be
那些黄金几乎总是如此
self-preservation because if it breaks
自我保护，因为如果它破裂
or dies in the process it's not gonna
或者在这个过程中死去它 不会
accomplish the goal right like suppose
像假设一样完成目标
you just build a little you have a
你只需要建立一个你有 一个
little robot and you tell it to go down
小机器人，你告诉它下来
the Starmark get here and and and get
Starmark 来到这里并且得到
you some food make your cookin Italian
你一些食物让你 乱打 意大利
dinner you know and then someone mugs it
你知道的晚餐，然后有人嘲笑它
and tries to break it down the way that
并试图打破它 的方式 ，
robot has an incentive to not destroy it
机器人有动力不破坏它
and defend itself or run away because
并保卫自己或逃跑，因为
otherwise it's gonna fail and cooking
否则它会失败和烹饪
you dinner it's not afraid of death but
你的晚餐是不怕 死 的 ，但
it really wants to complete the dinner
它 真的 想完成晚餐
cooking gold so it will have a
烹饪黄金所以它会有一个
self-preservation instinct continue
自我保护的本能继续
being a functional Asian yeah and and
是一个功能性的亚洲耶和华
similarly if you give any kind of warm
同样，如果你给任何一种温暖
and they she's go to an AGI
她们去了AGI
it's very likely they want to acquire
他们很可能想要获得
more resources so it can do that better
更多的资源， 所以它可以做得更好
and it's exactly from those sort of sub
它完全来自那些潜艇
goals that we might not have intended
我们可能没想过的目标
that but some of the concerns about AGI
这只是 对AGI的 一些 担忧
safety come you give it some goal which
安全来你给它一些目标
seems completely harmless and then
似乎完全无害然后
before you realize it it's also trying
在你意识到它之前它也在尝试
to do these other things which you
做你做的其他事情
didn't want it to do and it's moment be
不 希望它做的，它的时刻 是
smarter than us so so lastly and let me
比我们更聪明， 最后让我
pause just because I
暂停只是因为我
in a very kind of human centric way see
在一个很善良的人为主的方式看
fear of death is a valuable motivator
对死亡的恐惧是一种有价值的动力
haha so you don't think do you think
哈哈所以你觉得你没想到
that's an artifact of evolution so
那是进化的神器
that's the kind of mind space evolution
这就是心灵空间的 演变
created they were sort of almost
创造了 他们几乎
obsessed about self-preservation kind of
痴迷于自我保护的那种
genetic well you don't think that's
遗传很好，你不认为 那是
necessary to be afraid of death so not
因此不必害怕死亡
just a kind of sub goal of
只是一种次要目标
self-preservation just so you can keep
自我保护只是为了你可以保持
doing the thing but more fundamentally
从根本上 做 这件事
sort of have the finite thing like this
有点像这样有限的东西
ends for you at some point the
在某些 时候结束你 的
interesting do I think it's necessary
有趣的我认为这是必要的
before what precisely for intelligence
之前究竟是什么才智
but also for consciousness so for those
但对于那些意识也是如此
for both do you think really like a
对于你们两个，你认为真的像一个
finite death and the fear of it is
有限死亡和恐惧的是
important so before I can answer well
在我能够很好地回答之前很重要
before we can agree on whether it's
之前，我们可以 在它是否 同意
necessary for intelligence or for
对于情报或
consciousness we should be clear or how
意识我们应该清楚或如何
we define those two words because share
我们定义这两个词是因为共享
a lot of really smart people to find
很多真正聪明的人 ， 找到
them in very different ways I was in
他们的方式与我所处的方式截然不同
this on this panel and with AI experts
这个小组和AI专家
and they couldn't they couldn't agree on
他们不能不同意
how to define intelligence even so I
如何 定义情报即使如此 我
define intelligence simply as the
将情报简单地定义为
ability to accomplish complex goals
实现复杂目标的能力
I like your broad definition because
我喜欢你的广义定义，因为
again I don't want to be a carbon
再一次，我不想 成为一个碳
chauvinist right and in that case no it
沙文主义权利，在这种情况下 没有 它
certainly certainly doesn't require fear
当然肯定不需要恐惧
of death I would say alpha go alpha zero
死亡我会说alpha 去alpha零
is quite intelligent
非常聪明
I don't think alpha zero has any fear of
我不认为阿尔法零有任何恐惧
being turned off because it doesn't
被 关闭，因为它没有
understand the concept of that even and
理解 甚至和 那个 概念
and similarly consciousness I mean you
同样的意识我的意思是你
could certainly imagine very simple kind
当然可以想像 非常单纯 善良
of experience if you know if certain
经验，如果你知道如果确定
plants have any kind of experience I
植物有任何经验我
don't think they were afraid of dying if
不要以为他们是怕死 如果
there's nothing they can do about it
他们无能为力
anyway much so there wasn't that much
无论如何，没 那么多
value and but more seriously I think if
价值，但更严重的我认为如果
you ask not just about being conscious
你问不 只是 有意识地
but maybe having what you would
但也许有 你想要的
we might call an exciting life for you
我们可能会为您打造一个令人兴奋的生活
feel passion and I didn't really
感受激情，我真的不
appreciate the little things maybe there
欣赏 那里的 小事
but somehow maybe there perhaps it does
但不知怎的，也许它确实存在
help having having my backdrop today
帮助今天有我的 背景
it's finite you know let's let's make
它是有限的你知道让我们 做
the most of this this live to the
这个大部分活到了
fullest so if you if you knew you were
最充分的，如果你知道你是谁
gonna slip forever if you think you
如果你认为你会永远 滑倒
would change your yeah in some
会改变你的某些东西
perspective it would be an incredibly
透视它将是一个令人难以置信的
boring life living forever so in the
无聊的生活永远如此生活在
sort of loose subjective terms that you
你有点松散的主观用语
said of something exciting and something
谈到令人兴奋的事情
in this that other humans would
在这方面， 其他人会
understand I think is yeah it seems that
理解我认为是的，似乎 是
the the finiteness of it is important
它的有限性很重要
well the good news I have for you then
那么 我 给你的好消息 呢
is based on what we understand about
是基于什么我们都懂
cosmology everything is in our universe
宇宙论一切 都在我们的宇宙中
is Pro ultimately probably finite alone
是Pro最终可能 单独 有限
although pay crunch or bit or big what's
虽然 付出 紧张或有点或大的是什么
to expand anything yeah we couldn't have
扩展 任何我们不能拥有的东西
a Big Chill or a Big Crunch or a big rip
一阵大寒或 大嘎吱嘎嘎或大裂缝
or that's the big snap or death bubbles
或者那是 大爆炸或死亡的泡沫
all over more than a billion years away
遍布超过十亿年 远
so we should we certainly have vastly
所以我们当然应该有很多
more time than our ancestors thought but
比我们的祖先想的更多的时间， 但是
there is still it's still pretty hard to
还有它仍然很难
squeeze in an infinite number of compute
挤压无限数量的计算
cycles even though there are some
即使有一些循环也是如此
loophole let's just might be possible
漏洞让我们有可能
but I think I you know some people like
但我想 我知道有些人 喜欢
to say that you should live as if you're
说 你应该像你一样生活
about you're gonna die in five years or
关于 你将在 五年内 死亡 或
something that sort of optimal maybe
也许 是那种 最佳的 东西
it's a good it subs we should build our
这是一个良好的IT 潜艇 上，建立我们
civilization as if it's all finite to be
文明仿佛它都是有限的
on the safe side right exactly so you
在安全方面的权利 正是 这样你
mentioned in defining intelligence as
在将情报定义为
the ability solve complex goals where
能力解决 复杂的目标，其中
would you draw a line how would you try
你会画一条线怎么试试？
to define human level intelligence and
定义人类的智力和
superhuman level intelligence where this
超人 级智能在哪里
consciousness part of that definition no
意识的一部分定义没有
consciousness does not come into this
意识不会进入这个
definition so so I think your
定义所以我认为你的
intelligence is it's a spectrum but
智能是一种频谱但是
there are very many different kinds of
有很多种不同的
goals you can have you can have a goal
你可以拥有的目标可以实现目标
to be a good chess player a good goal
成为一名优秀的棋手一个好目标
player a good car driver
球员一个好车司机
a good investor good poet etc so
一个好的投资者好诗人等等
intelligence that bind by its very
被它非常束缚的智慧
nature isn't something you can measure
自然不是你可以衡量的东西
but it's one number overall goodness no
但这是一个数字 整体的善良没有
no there are some people who are more
没有一些人 更多
better at this some people are better
更好的是，有些人更好
than that um right now we have machines
比 那个我 现在有机器
that are much better than us at some
在某些方面比我们 好得多
very narrow tasks like multiplying large
非常狭窄的任务，如倍增大
numbers fast memorizing large databases
数字快速记忆 大型数据库
playing chess playing go and soon
下棋很快就去玩了
driving cars but there's still no
驾驶汽车， 但仍然没有
machine that can match a human child in
可以匹配人类孩子的机器
general intelligence but but artificial
一般情报但但是人为的
general intelligence AGI in the name of
一般情报AGI的名义
your course of course that is by its
你的课程 当然是由它
very definition the the quests the build
非常定义构建的任务
a mission in seen that can do everything
看到的任务 可以做 任何事情
as well as we can up to the old holy
以及我们可以达到旧圣
grail of AI from from back to its
人工智能从后面到它的圣杯
inception and then 60s if that ever
开始，然后60年代，如果有的话
happens of course I think it's gonna be
当然， 我认为它会发生
the biggest transition in the history of
历史上最大的转变
life on earth but it but it doesn't
地球上的 生命， 但 它没有
necessarily have to wait the big impact
必须 等待重大影响
about until machines are better than us
直到机器比我们好
at knitting the really big change
在编织真正的巨大变化
doesn't come exactly the moment they're
不 来 正好 他们 的那一刻
better than us at everything
一切都比我们好
the really big change comes first there
真正的大变化首先 出现在那里
big changes when they start becoming
当他们开始变得巨大的变化
better at us at doing most of the jobs
在我们更好地在做大部分 工作
that we do because that's it can takes
我们这样做是因为 它 可以
away much of the demand for human labor
走多的人的劳动的需求
and then the really whopping change
然后是非常惊人的变化
comes when they become better than us at
当他们变得比我们更好的时候来
AI research right right because right
人工智能研究正确， 因为正确
now the timescale of AI researcher is
现在AI 研究员的时间表 是
limited by the human research and
受到人类研究的限制
development cycle of years typically at
多年的发展周期通常在
all along the tape from one release of
从 一个版本 的磁带一直到
some software or iPhone or whatever to
一些软件或 iPhone 或 任何 以
the next but once once we have once
下一次，但 有一次 我们 有一次
Google can replace 40,000 engineers by
谷歌可以替代4万名工程师
40,000 equivalent pieces of software or
40,000个等效的软件或
whatever right then that doesn't there's
无论正确 再不 有
no reason that has to be years it can be
没有理由 必须是年也可以 是
in principle much faster and the
原则上要快得多
timescale of future progress in AI and
人工智能和人工智能未来发展的 时间表
also all of science and technology will
所有 的科学和 技术都会
will be driven by machines not
将由机器驱动而不是
so it's this point simple point which
所以这就是简单点
lives right this incredibly fun
生活在这令人难以置信的乐趣
controversy about whether it can be an
关于它是否可以成为一个争议
intelligence explosion so-called
所谓的情报爆炸
singularities Vernor Vinge called it
奇异的 Vernor Vinge称之为 奇点
that the idea is articulated by IJ good
IJ很好地 表达了这个想法
obviously way back fifties but you can
显然可以追溯到五十年代，但你可以
see Alan Turing and others thought about
看到阿兰图灵和其他人的想法
it even earlier not did you ask me what
它甚至更早 不是 你 问我什么
exactly what I define England's yeah so
正是我所定义的英格兰 是的
this the the glib answer is it to say
这个滑稽的答案就是这么说的
something which is better than us at all
总比我们好的东西
cognitive tasks will look better than
认知 任务看起来会比
any human and all cognitive tasks but
任何人类和所有认知任务，但
the really interesting bar I think goes
我 觉得这个真正有趣的酒吧
a little bit lower than that actually
实际上 比 实际 低一点
it's when they can when they're better
当他们变得更好的时候就可以了
than us it AI programming and can a
比我们人工智能编程还可以
general learning so that they can can if
一般学习， 以便 他们可以
they want to get better than I said
他们希望得到 更好的比我说
anything by just studying so they're
通过 只是 学习，使他们是 什么
better is a keyword and better as
更好的是 关键字，更好
towards this kind of spectrum of the
对这种频谱
complexity of goals it's able to
它能够实现目标的复杂性
accomplish yeah so another way to so no
完成是的另一种方式，所以没有
and that's certainly a very clear
这当然是非常清楚的
definition of human law so there's it's
人类 法律的 定义 所以就是这样
almost like a sea that's rising you
几乎就像一个正在崛起的大海
could do more and more and more things
可以做多 和 越来越多 的 东西
as a graphic that you show it's really
作为一个 你 真正 表现 出来的 图形
nice way to put it so there's some Peaks
漂亮的方式把 它 所以有 一些峰
that and there's an ocean level
这一点，有一个海平面
elevating and you saw more and more
提升，你看到越来越 多
problems but you know just kind of to
但是你知道的问题
take a pause and we took a bunch of
暂停一下，我们拿了一堆
questions and a lot of social networks
问题和很多社交网络
and a bunch of people asked a sort of a
还有一群人问了 一个问题
slightly different direction on
上稍微不同的方向
creativity and and things like that
创造力和类似的东西
perhaps aren't a peak the it's you know
也许 你不知道它 是一个高峰
human beings are flawed and perhaps
人类也有缺陷
better means having being a having
更好意味着拥有
contradiction being fought in some way
矛盾正以某种方式进行
so let me sort of yeah
所以让我有点耶
start and start easy first of all so you
首先开始并轻松开始 ，这样你
have a lot of cool equations let me ask
有很多很酷的方程让我问
what's your favorite equation first of
你最喜欢的方程式是什么？
all I know they're all like your
我知道他们都像你一样
children but like which one is that it's
孩子，但像哪一个是 它的
the master key of
的万能钥匙
want the mechanics of the microworld
想要微观世界的机制
this equation to protect you like
这个方程来保护你 喜欢
everything to do with atoms molecules
与原子分子有关
and all that we have yeah so okay it's a
而我们拥有的一切都是如此， 这是一个
quantum mechanics is certainly a
量子力学肯定是一个
beautiful mysterious formulation of our
我们美丽的神秘配方
world so I'd like to sort of ask you
世界所以我 想问你一下
just as an example it perhaps doesn't
作为一个例子，它可能没有
have the same beauty as physics does but
拥有和物理一样的美，但是
in mathematics abstract the Andrew Wiles
在数学中抽象安德鲁威尔斯
who proved the firm as last theta so he
谁证明了 公司是最后的theta 所以他
just saw this recently and it kind of
刚看到这个，有点儿
caught my eye a little bit this is three
引起了我的注意， 这是 三点
hundred fifty eight years after it was
在它之后的 一百五十八年
conjectured so this very simple
猜想这很简单
formulation everybody tried to prove it
每个人都试图证明这一点
everybody failed and say here's this guy
每个人都失败了， 并说这是这个家伙
comes along and eventually it proves it
走来 并 最终证明了这一点
and then fails to prove it and proves it
然后无法证明并证明它
again in 94 and he said like the moment
又在94， 他说喜欢的那一刻
when everything connected into place the
当一切都连接到位
in an interview said it was so
在接受采访时说是这样的
indescribably beautiful that moment when
那个时刻难以形容的美丽
you finally realized the connecting
你终于实现了连接
piece of two conjectures he said it was
他说这是猜测的两个猜想
so indescribably beautiful it was so
它是 如此 令人难以置信的美丽
simple and so elegant I couldn't
简单而优雅我不能
understand how I'd missed it and I just
明白我是如何错过它而我只是
stared at it in disbelief for twenty
难以置信地盯着它二十岁
minutes then then during the day I
分钟后，那一天 我 在
walked around the department and at
走 在 部门和 周围
Keamy keep coming back to my desk
Keamy 继续回到我的办公桌前
looking to see if it was still there it
期待它是否还在 那里
was still there I couldn't contain
还在那里， 我无法控制
myself I was so excited it was the most
我自己很兴奋， 这是最多的
important moment on my working life
我 工作生涯的重要时刻
nothing I ever do again will mean as
我再也做不了什么意思
much so that particular moment and it
那么特别的时刻和 它
kind of made me think of what would it
有点让我想到 它会是什么
take and I think we have all been there
我想 我们都 去过那里
at small levels maybe let me ask have
在较小的水平 也许让我问
you had a moment like that in your life
你在生活中 有 这样的 一个时刻
where you just had an ideas like wow yes
在那里你有一个 想法， 如哇是的
I wouldn't
我不会
self and the same breath as Andrew wilds
自我和安德鲁野性一样的呼吸
but I've certainly had a number of um
但我当然有一些嗯
aha moments mo when I realized something
啊哈时刻莫 当我意识到的东西
very cool about physics just as
关于物理 非常 酷，就像
completely made my head explode in fact
事实上，我的头脑完全爆炸了
some of my favorite discoveries I made
我做的一些我最喜欢的发现
later I later realize if they had been
后来我才意识到他们是不是
discovered earlier someone who sometimes
早些时候发现有人
got quite famous for it so I find this
我很有名， 所以我 找到了
too late for me to even publish it but
我甚至发布它的时间太迟了
that doesn't diminish in any way an
不以任何 方式 减少
emotional experience you have when you
你有的情感体验
realize it like yeah Wow yeah
意识到它就像是啊哇呀
so what would it take and at that moment
那么怎样才能 在那 一刻
that wow that was yours in a moment so
那哇，这是你在瞬间 使
what do you think it takes for an
你觉得什么需要的
intelligent system and a GI system an AI
智能系统和GI 系统AI
system to have a moment like that that's
系统有一个像那样的时刻
a tricky question because there are
一个棘手的问题，因为有
actually two parts to it right one of
实际上它是两个部分之一
them is cannot accomplish that proof it
他们无法做到证明这一点
cannot prove that you can never write a
不能证明你永远不能写一个
to the N plus B to the N equals 3/2 that
到N加B到 N等于3/2那个
equals e to the N for all integers well
等于所有 整数的N到N
etc etc when when n is bigger than 2 the
等等等等时，当n 是大于 2 的 较大的
simply in any question about
只是在任何问题
intelligence can you build machines that
智能可以为您打造的机器，
are that intelligent and I think by the
那是聪明的，我想是 的
time we get a machine that can
我们得到的机器可以
independently come up with that level of
独立提出那个级别
proofs probably quite close to AGI the
证据可能与AGI非常接近
second question is a question about
第二个问题是 关于 问题
consciousness when will we will willins
意识什么时候我们会意志
how likely is it that such a machine
这种机器有多大可能性
will actually have any experience at all
实际上有什么经验可言
as opposed to just being like a zombie
而不是仅仅是 像 一个僵尸
and would we expect it to have some sort
我们希望它有某种形式
of emotional response to this or
对此或的情绪反应
anything at all I can to human emotion
任何事我都能感受到人类的情感
work no but when it accomplishes its
工作没有，但当它完成它
machine goal it did the views it to
机器目标它做了它的意见
somehow it's something very positive and
不知它的东西很正 ，
right and and sublime and and and and
对和崇高和 和和
deeply meaningful I would certainly hope
非常有意义， 我 当然希望
that if in the future we do create
如果 将来 我们确实创造了
machines that are our peers or even our
机器是我们的同行 甚至我们的
dis
DIS
since yeah I would certainly hope that
既然是的，我当然 希望如此
they do have this sort of sublime
他们确实有这种崇高
sublime appreciation of life in a way my
崇高的生活欣赏我 的 方式
absolutely worst nightmare would be that
绝对最糟糕的噩梦将是
in at some point in the future the
在未来的某个时刻
distant future maybe I cost much as
遥远的未来也许 我花了很多钱
teeming with all this post biological
充满 了所有这些后生物学
life doing all the seemingly cool stuff
生活做所有看似很酷的东西
and maybe the fun last humans or the
也许乐趣最后人类 或
time era our species eventually fizzles
时间 的时代我们的物种最终fizzles
out we'll be like well that's ok because
出我们就会像好 没关系 ，因为
we're so proud of our descendants here
我们为这里的后代感到骄傲
and look what I like my most nightmare
看看我 喜欢的我最噩梦
is that we haven't solved the
是我们还没有解决的
consciousness problem and we haven't
意识问题，我们没有
realized that these are all the zombies
意识到这些都是僵尸
they're not aware of anything anymore
他们不再知道任何事了
than the tape recorders it has an any
比录音机还要好
kind of experience so the whole thing
那种经历所以整件事
has just become a play for empty benches
刚刚成为 空旷的长椅
that would be like the ultimate zombie
这将是最终的僵尸
apocalypse me III would much rather in
启示录我很喜欢
that case that we have these beings
那种情况我们有这些生命
which just really appreciate how how
这真的很感激如何
amazing it is
太神奇了
and in that picture what would be the
在那张照片中会是什么
role of creativity we had a few people
创造力的作用我们有几个人
ask about creativity do you think when
问你有关创造力的想法吗？
you think about intelligence I mean
你想想 我的意思
certainly the the story told the
当然这个故事告诉 了
beginning of your book involved you know
你的书的开头涉及到你知道
creating movies and so on yeah sort of
制作电影等呀 之类的
making making money you know you can
赚钱，你知道你可以
make a lot of money in our modern world
在 我们的现代世界赚很多钱
with music and movies so if you are
有音乐和电影，如果 你是
intelligent system you may want to get
你可能想获得智能系统
good at that yeah but that's not
擅长那个 但是那 不是
necessarily what I mean by creativity is
我的意思是 创造力
it important on that complex goals where
这对复杂的目标非常重要
the sea is rising for there to be
大海正在崛起
something creative creative or am I
什么 创意创意或我
being very human centric and thinking
以人为本，思考
creativity somehow special
创造力有点特别
relative to intelligence my hunch is
相对于智力， 我的 预感是
that we should think your creativity
我们应该考虑你的创造力
simply as an aspect of intelligence and
只是作为情报 和方面的一个方面
[Music]
[音乐]
we
我们
we have to be very careful with with
我们必须非常小心
human vanity we had we have this
人类的虚荣我们拥有这个
tendency to very often one and say as
倾向于经常一个并说出来
soon as machines can do something we try
机器可以做我们尝试的事情
to diminish it that's a long but that's
减少它，这是一个很长但是 那个
not like real intelligence you know
不像你知道的真实情报
you're the night trader or there were or
你是 夜间交易员还是有或者
this or that or the other thing maybe if
这个或那个或 另一件事可能 如果
we ask ourselves to write down a
我们要求自己写下来
definition of what we actually mean by
我们实际意味着 什么的定义
being creative what we mean by Andrew
创造性我们所说的安德鲁
Wiles what he did there for example
怀尔斯他的所作所为有例如
don't we often mean that someone takes
我们不是经常意味着某人需要
you very unexpected leap mm-hmm it's not
你非常意外的飞跃mm-hmm它不是
like taking feet 573 and multiplying in
喜欢脚573并乘以
my 224 by justice step of
我的224 正义步骤
straightforward cookbook like rules
简单的 食谱就像规则
right if this you may be making you even
权利 ，如果这个你 可能让你连
make a connection between two things
在两件事之间建立联系
that people have never thought was
人们从未想过的是
connect very surprising or something
连接非常令人惊讶或什么的
like that I think I think this is an
就像 我 认为我认为这是一个
aspect of intelligence and this is some
智力方面，这是一些
actually one of the most important
实际上是最重要的一个
aspect of it maybe the reason we humans
它的方面可能 是我们人类的原因
are tend to be better at it than
都趋向 于 比 它更好
traditional computers is because it's
传统电脑是因为它
something that comes more naturally if
东西 来更自然，如果
you're a neural network then if you're a
你是一个神经网络然后如果你是一个
traditional logic gate based computer
传统的逻辑 门 计算机
machine
机
you know we physically have all these
你知道我们身体上有这些
connections and you activate here
连接 ，你在这里激活
activator here activate here ping you
激活器在这里激活ping你
know I my hunch is that if we ever build
知道我的预感是 ，如果我们 建立
a machine where you could just give it
一台机器， 你可以只 给它
the task hey hey you say hey you know I
任务嘿嘿，你说，嘿，你知道我
just realized that I have I want to
刚才意识到我有我想要的
travel around the world instead this
环游世界而不是 这个
months can you teach my eight a GI
几个月你可以教我的八个GI
course for me and it's like ok I'll do
当然对我来说就好了 我会做的
it and it does everything that you would
它会做 你 想做的 一切
have done and they provides us and so
已经做了，他们提供了 我们 等等
yeah that that would in my mind involve
是的，在我看来会涉及到
a lot of creativity yeah so I had such a
很多创造力是啊所以我有这样的
beautiful way to put it I think we do
美丽的方式，我认为我们这样做
try to grab grasp at the you know the
试着抓住你所知道的
definition of intelligence is everything
智力的 定义 就是一切
we don't understand how how to build so
我们不明白如何建立如此
like so we as humans try to find things
就像我们人类试图 找到的东西一样
well that we have on machines don't
好吧， 我们在机器上没有
happen maybe creativity is just one of
发生也许 创造力 只是其中之一
the things one of the words we use to
我们习惯使用的词之一
describe that that's really interesting
描述 那真的很 有趣
where to put it out
在哪里 把它拿出来
think we need to be that defensive I
我认为我们需要成为防守者
don't think anything good comes out of
不要认为有任何好处
saying oh we're somehow special you know
说哦，我们有点特别你知道
I it's contrariwise there are many
相反， 我 有很多
examples in history of we're trying to
我们正在尝试的历史中的例子
pretend that were somehow superior to
假装在某种程度上优于
all other intelligent beings has led the
所有其他智慧生物领导了
pretty bad results right
非常糟糕的结果吧
Nazi Germany they said that they were
纳粹德国他们说他们是
somehow superior to other people today
今天以某种方式优于其他人
we still do a lot of cruelty to animals
我们仍然对 动物 做了很多残忍
by saying that we're social superiors
说我们是社会上司
and how and the other they can't feel
他们怎么和别人都感觉不到
pain
痛
slavery was justified by the same kind
奴隶制是有道理的
of really weak weak arguments and and I
真弱的弱论点和我
don't think if we actually go ahead and
不要以为 我们是否真的继续 前进
build artificial general intelligence it
建立人工一般情报吧
can do things better than us I don't
可以比我们做得更好，但事实并非如此
think we should try to found our
我认为我们应该努力 找到我们的
self-worth on some sort of bogus claims
某种虚假声称的自我价值
of superiority in in terms of our
优势在 方面 我们
intelligence I think it's we shouldn't
情报我认为我们不应该这样做
stand Joe find our calling and then the
乔找到了我们的电话， 然后是
meaning of life from from experiences
来自经验的生命意义
that we have right you know I can have I
我们对你知道 我可以拥有我
can have very meaningful experiences
可以有非常有意义的经历
even if there are other people who are
即使有其他人
smarter than me you know when I go to
比我聪明，你 知道，当我去
faculty meeting here and I was talking
教师在这里开会，我在说话
about something that I certainly realize
关于我当然意识到的事情
oh boy he has a Nobel Prize he has a
哦，他有诺贝尔奖，他有一个
Nobel Prize he has no pride I don't have
诺贝尔奖他没有自豪感我没有
what does that make me enjoy life any
是什么让我享受 生活
less or would enjoy talking those people
少或者喜欢和那些人说话
less of course not see my and the
少 当然不会看到我和
contrariwise I I feel very honored and
相反 ，我感到非常荣幸和
privileged to get to interact with with
特权去 与互动
other very intelligent beings that are
其他非常聪明的存在
better than me a lot of stuff so I don't
比我好很多 东西，所以我没有
think there's any reason why we can't
认为我们不能有任何理由
have the same approach with with
与...有 相同的方法
intelligent machines that's a really
真正的智能机器
interesting so people don't often think
有趣，所以人们 不经常思考
about that they think about when there's
关于他们 什么 时候 考虑的 事情
going if there's machines that are more
如果有更多的机器去
intelligent you naturally think that
智能你 自然会想到
that's not going to be a beneficial type
这不会是一种有益的类型
of intelligence you don't realise it
你没有意识到的情报
could be
可能
you know like peers of Nobel Prizes that
你知道诺贝尔奖的同行吗？
that would be just fun to talk with and
这将是公正的乐趣与 交谈，
they might be clever about certain
他们可能对某些事情很聪明
topics and you can have fun having a few
主题， 你可以享受一些乐趣
drinks with them so well another example
与他们一起喝酒的另一个例子
is we can all relate to it why it
我们都可以 将它 与 它 联系 起来
doesn't have to be a terrible thing to
并不一定是一件可怕的事情
be impressed the friends of people are
印象深刻的是人们的朋友
even smarter than us all around is when
比我们周围更聪明的是什么时候
when you and I were both two years old I
当你和我两岁的时候我
mean our parents were much more
意味着我们的父母更多
intelligent than us right here worked
比我们聪明，就 在这里工作
out okay yeah because their goals were
好的， 是的，因为 他们的目标是
aligned with our goals
符合我们的 目标
yeah and that I think is really the
是的，我认为真的 是
number one T issue we have to solve its
我们必须解决它的 头号 问题
value align the value alignment problem
值对齐值对齐问题
exactly because people who see too many
正是因为看到太多的人
Hollywood movies with lousy science
好莱坞电影与糟糕的科学
fiction plot lines they worry about the
小说的情节线索，他们担心
wrong thing right they worry about some
说错话 的权利 ，他们担心一些
machines only turning evil it's not
机器只会变坏而不是
malice they wish that the issue probably
他们希望这个问题 可能是恶意的
concerned its competence by definition
从定义上讲它的能力
intelligent makes you makes you very
智能让你非常善良
competent if you have a more intelligent
如果你有一个更聪明的人，你就胜任
goal playing mr. computer playing as the
打球的先生。电脑玩 的
less intelligent one and when we define
不那么 聪明，我们定义时
intelligence is the ability to
智力是 能力
accomplish go winning right it's gonna
完成胜利吧
be the more intelligent one that wins my
是一个赢得我的聪明人
and if you have a human and then you
如果你有一个人，那么你
have an AGI and that's more intelligent
有一个AGI， 这更聪明
in all ways and they have different
在所有方面， 他们有不同
goals guess who's gonna get their way
目标猜猜谁会找到自己的方式
right so I was just reading about I was
对，所以我只是在读我的故事
just reading about this particular
只是阅读这个特别的
rhinoceros species that was driven
被驱赶的犀牛物种
extinct just a few years ago bummer is
灭绝只是在几年前 是无赖
looking at this cute picture mommy run
看着这张可爱的照片妈妈跑
oestrus with it's it's child you know
你知道，这是它的孩子
and why did we humans private extinction
为什么我们人类会私下灭绝
wasn't because we were evil Rhino haters
不是因为我们是邪恶的犀牛仇敌
right as a whole it was just because we
总的来说，这只是因为我们
our goals weren't aligned with those of
我们的目标 与 那些 目标 不一致
the rhinoceros and it didn't work out so
犀牛， 它没有成功
well for the rhinoceros because we were
以及 为犀牛，因为我们
more intelligent right so I think it's
更聪明，所以我认为是
just so important that if we ever do
非常重要，如果我们做的话
build AGI before we
在我们之前建立AGI
we have to make sure that it it learns
我们必须确保 它学到它
to understand our goals that it adopts
了解我们采用的目标
our goals and it retains those goals so
我们的目标，它保留了这些目标
the cool interesting problem there is
这是一个很酷的有趣问题
being able us as human beings trying to
能够我们人类试图
formulate our values so you know you
制定我们的价值观， 让你了解你
could think of the United States
可以 认为 ， 美国 的
Constitution as a as a way that people
宪法作为一种 人 的 方式
sat down at the time a bunch of white
当时 坐 了一堆白色
men but which is a good example I should
男人，但我应该是一个很好的例子
we should say they formulated the goals
我们应该说他们制定 了目标
for this country and a lot of people
对于这个国家和很多人
agree that those goals actually hold up
同意 这些 目标确实有用
pretty well that's an interesting
很好，这是一个 有趣的
formulation of values and failed
价值观的制定和 失败
miserably in other ways so for the value
在其他方面惨遭如此价值
alignment problem and a solution to it
对齐问题及其解决方案
we have to be able to put on paper or in
我们必须 能够把在纸上或
in in a program human values how
在一个程序中人类如何评价
difficult do you think that is very but
难，你认为这是非常，但
it's so important we really have to give
它是如此重要，我们真的必须给予
it our best and it's difficult for two
这是我们 最好的， 两个人 很难
separate reasons there's the technical
单独的原因 是技术性的
value alignment problem of figuring out
搞清楚的值对准问题
just how to make machines understand our
只是如何让机器了解我们的
goals adopt them and retain them and
目标采用它们并 保留它们
then there's a separate part of it the
然后有一个 单独的部分
philosophical part whose values anyway
无论如何，哲学部分的价值观
and since we it's not like we have any
因为我们不像我们有任何东西
great consensus on this planet on values
在这个星球上就价值观达成了共识
how what mechanism should we create them
我们应该如何创建它们
to aggregate and decide okay what's a
聚合并 决定什么是好的
good compromise right at that second
正好在那一秒妥协
discussion can't this be left the tech
讨论不能留给技术
nerds like myself right that's right and
像我这样的书呆子是正确 的
if we refuse to talk about it and then
如果我们拒绝谈论 它，然后
AGI gets built who's gonna be actually
AGI建成 谁将是实际的
making the decision about whose values
决定谁的价值观
it's gonna be a bunch of dudes and some
这将是一群 男人 和一些人
tech company yeah yeah and are they
科技公司是的耶和华，是他们
necessarily - it's it's so
必然- 就是这样
representative of all humankind that we
我们 所有人类的代表
want to just entrusted to them or they
想要委托给他们或他们
even is uniquely qualified to speak the
甚至是唯一有资格 说话 的人
future human happiness just because
未来的人类幸福只是因为
they're good at programming any I I'd
他们擅长编程 我倒是 任何 我
much rather have this be a really
更确切地说这是真的
inclusive conversation but do you think
包容性对话， 但你认为
it's possible sort of so you create a
它有可能让你创造一个
beautiful vision that includes so the
美丽的愿景， 包括 所以
diversity cultural diversity and various
多样性文化多样性 和各种
specs on discussing rights freedoms
关于讨论权利自由的规范
human dignity but how hard is it to come
人的尊严，但 它 有多难
to that consensus do you think it's
那个共识你认为 是 吗？
certainly a really important thing that
当然是一件非常重要的 事情
we should all try to do but do you think
我们都应该尝试做但你 认为
it's feasible I I think there's no
这是可行的II 认为没有
better way to guarantee failure than to
更好的方法来保证失败而不是
try to refuse to talk about it or or
试图拒绝谈论 它或 或
refuse to try and I also think it's a
拒绝尝试，我也认为这是一个
really bad strategy to say okay let's
非常糟糕的策略，说好吧 让我们
first have a discussion for a long time
首先要讨论很长一段时间
and then once we reach complete
然后一旦我们完成
consensus then we'll try to load it into
然后我们会尝试加载它
the Machine know it we shouldn't let
机器 知道我们不应该让它
perfect be the enemy of good instead we
完美是我们的好敌人
should start with the kindergarten
应该从幼儿园开始
ethics - pretty much everybody agrees on
道德 - 几乎 每个人都 同意
and put that into our machines now we're
现在 我们 把它放进我们的机器中
not doing that even look at the you know
甚至不看你知道的那样做
anyone who builds this passenger
建造这名乘客的人
aircraft wants it to never under any
飞机希望它 永远不会在任何情况下
circumstances fly into a building or
情况飞入建筑物或
mountain right yet the September 11
山右，但9月11日
hijackers were able to do that and even
劫机者能够做到这一点 甚至是
more embarrassingly you know and that he
更尴尬的是你知道和他
has Lubitz this depressed
鲁比茨对此感到沮丧
Germanwings pilot when he flew his
德国之翼飞行时飞行员
passenger jet into the Alps killing over
客机飞入阿尔卑斯山杀死过来
a hundred people he just told the
他刚刚告诉 了一百 个人
autopilot to do it he told the freaking
自动驾驶仪 做到这一点，他告诉怪物
computer to change the altitude 200
电脑改变海拔高度200
meters and even though it had the GPS
米，即使它有GPS
maps everything the computer was like
映射计算机的所有内容
okay no so which we should take those
好吧不 ，我们应该采取那些
very basic values though where the
非常基本的价值观虽然在哪里
problem is not that we don't agree that
问题不是我们 不同意的
maybe the problem is just we've been too
也许问题就在于我们一直 都是
lazy to try to put it into our machines
懒得试着把它放进我们的机器里
and make sure but from now on air
并确保从现在开始
airplanes will just which all have
所有人都拥有飞机
computers in them but we'll just never
在他们的电脑， 但 我们将 永远 都 不会
just refuse to do something like that go
只是拒绝做那样的事情
into safe mode
进入安全模式
maybe lock the cockpit door or than here
也许锁定驾驶舱门 或比这里
at the airport and and there's so much
在机场 ，有这么多
other technology in our world as well
我们世界的其他技术也是如此
now where it's really quite becoming
现在，它真正成为了现实
quite timely to put in some sort of very
很 及时地投入 某种非常
basic values like this even in cars we
这样的基本价值即使在汽车我们也是如此
were have enough vehicle terrorism
有足够的车辆恐怖主义
attacks by now of you love different
现在你的攻击爱不同
trucks and bands into pedestrians that
卡车和乐队 到 行人 说
it's not at all a crazy idea to just
这根本不是一个疯狂的想法， 只是
have that hardwired into the car just
把它硬连接到汽车里
yeah there are a lot of there's always
是的，有很多总是存在的
gonna be people who for some reason want
会是出于某种原因想要的人
to harm others
伤害他人
most of those people don't have the
大多数人都没有
technical expertise to figure out how to
技术专长，以弄清楚如何
work around something like that so if
解决这样的事情 ，如果
the car just won't do it
汽车就是不会这样做的
it helps it let's start there so there's
它帮助它让我们从那里开始吧
a lot of that's a great point so not not
很多这都是一个很好的观点，所以不是没有
chasing perfect there's a lot of things
追逐完美有很多东西
that a lot that most of the world agrees
这是世界上大多数人都同意的事情
on yeah and this look there let's start
是的， 这 看起来让我们开始吧
there and and then once we start there
那里，然后一旦我们开始
we'll also get into the habit of having
我们也 养成了拥有的习惯
these kind of conversations about okay
这些 关于好的谈话
what else should we put in here and I
还有什么 我们 应该 放在这里 和 我
have these discussions this should be a
这些 讨论 应该是一个
gradual process then great so but that
渐进的过程然后很好，但那
also means describing these things and
也意味着描述这些事情
describing it to a machine
将它描述到 一台机器上
so one thing we had a few conversation
所以有一件事我们 进行了几次 谈话
was Stephen Wolfram I'm not sure if
是 史蒂芬·沃尔夫勒姆 我不知道，如果
you're familiar with Stephen but yeah I
你熟悉斯蒂芬，但是 我
know quite well so he is you know he
知道得很 清楚，所以他知道他
played you know works with a bunch of
玩过你知道一堆作品
things but you know cellular automata
事情，但你知道细胞自动机
are these simple computable things these
这些是简单的可计算的东西吗？
computation systems and he kind of
计算系统和他那种
mentioned that you know we probably have
提到你知道 我们可能有
already within these systems already
已经在这些系统中
something that's AGI meaning like we
东西 ，就像我们AGI意义
just don't know it because we can't talk
只是不知道 因为 我们不能说话
to it so if you give me this chance to
它 ， 因此，如果你给 我这个机会，
try to try to release form a question
试着尝试 发布一个问题
out of this is I think it's an
出于这个原因，我认为 这是一个
interesting idea to think that we can
有趣的想法，认为我们可以
have intelligent systems but we don't
有智能 系统，但 我们没有
know how to describe something to them
知道如何向他们描述一些东西
and they can't communicate with us I
他们无法与我们沟通 我
know you're doing a little bit work an
知道你在做一点点工作 的
explainable AI trying to get AI to
可解释的人工智能试图让人工智能
explain itself so what are your thoughts
交待 所以你有什么想法
of natural language processing or some
自然语言处理或一些
kind of other communication how how does
那种其他沟通怎么办
the AI explain something to us how do we
AI向我们解释了我们是如何做到的
explain something to it to machines or
向机器 或 机器解释一些东西
you think of it differently so there are
你认为它不同 所以有
two separate parts to your question
你问题的两个独立部分
there are them one of them has to do
有 他们中的一个 必须做
with communication which is super
与超级的沟通
interesting you don't get that insect
有趣的是你 没有得到那种 昆虫
the other is whether we already have AGI
另一个是我们是否已经拥有 AGI
but we just haven't noticed it yeah
但我们只是没 注意到它
right there I beg to differ right and
就在那里，我求求不同的权利
don't think there's anything in any
不要以为任何东西都没有
cellular automaton or anything or the
细胞自动机或任何东西或
internet itself or whatever that has
互联网本身或其他任何东西
artificial
人造
it didn't really do exactly everything
它并没有真正 完成所有事情
we humans can do better I think today if
如果， 我 认为今天 人类 可以 做得更好
the day that happens when that happens
发生 这种 情况的那一天
we will very soon notice we will
我们很快就会发现我们 将
probably notice even before andif
甚至 在 andif 之前可能会注意到
because in a very very big way but for
因为在非常大的方面，但是
the second part though sorry so the
第二部分虽然很抱歉所以
because you you have this beautiful way
因为你有 这种美好的 方式
to formulating consciousness as as a you
像你一样制定意识
know as information processing you can
知道你可以做的信息处理
think of intelligence and information
想想 情报和信息
processing and this you can think of the
处理 这个你可以想到的
entire universe there's these particles
整个宇宙都有这些粒子
and these systems roaming around that
而这些系统在那里漫游
have this information processing power
拥有这种信息处理能力
you don't you don't think there is
你不是不认为有
something with the power to process
有 能力处理的 东西
information in the way that we human
信息以我们人类的方式
beings do that's out there that that
众生就是这样做的
needs to be sort of connected to it
需要进行排序 的连接到它
seems a little bit philosophical perhaps
或许似乎有点哲学
but there's something compelling to the
但有一些令人信服的东西
idea that the power is already there
认为权力已经存在
would you know yes the focus should be
你会知道 是的焦点应该是
more on these I'm being able to
更多关于这些我能够
communicate with it mhm well I agree
它 MHM 以及我 同意 沟通
that that and some in a certain sense
在某种意义上说那和那些
the hardware processing power is already
硬件处理能力已经存在
out there because our universe itself
因为 我们的宇宙本身
can think of it as being a computer
可以把它想象成一台电脑
already right it's constantly computing
已经对了，它一直在计算
what water waves have evolved the water
什么水浪已经 发展水
waves and the river Charles and how to
波浪和 查尔斯 河 如何
move the air molecules around that s
将空气分子移动到那个s周围
Lloyd has pointed out my colleague here
劳埃德 在这里 指出 了我的同事
that you can even in a very rigorous way
你甚至可以以非常严格的方式
think of our entire universe as being a
把我们整个宇宙想象成一个
quantum computer it's pretty clear that
量子计算机是很明显 ，
our universe supports this amazing
我们的宇宙支持这个惊人
processing power because you can even
处理能力，因为你 甚至 可以
the within this physics computer that we
在 我们的物理计算机 内
live in right we can even build actually
住在 右边，我们甚至可以建造
laptops and stuff so clearly the power
笔记本电脑和东西如此清晰的力量
is there it's just that most of the
它就是那里的大部分
compute power that nature has it's in my
计算，自然有它在 我的 动力
opinion kind of wasting on boring stuff
意见浪费在无聊的东西上
like simulating yet another ocean wave
比如模拟另一个海浪
somewhere where no one is even looking
在某个地方甚至没人看
right so in a sense of what life does
这就是 生活的意义所在
what we are doing when we build
我们在建设时正在做什么
computers is where we channeling all
计算机是 我们引导所有人的地方
this compute that nature is doing anyway
无论如何 ，大自然在做这个计算
into doing things that are more
做更多的事情
interesting than just yet another ocean
有趣的不仅仅是 另一个 海洋
wave you know and let's do something
挥手你知道，让我们做点什么
cool here so the raw hardware power
这里很酷，所以原始的硬件能力
and sherbet and then and even just like
和果子露然后甚至就像
computing what's gonna happen for the
计算将要发生的事情
next five seconds in this water ball you
接下来的 五秒钟，这个水球你
know it takes in a ridiculous amount of
知道它发生在一个可笑的金额
compute if you do it on a human computer
如果你在人类计算机上进行计算
in yeah
是的
this water ball was did it but that does
这个水球做到了但是确实如此
not mean this water bottle has AGI and
并不意味着这个水瓶有AGI和
because AGI means it should also be able
因为AGI意味着它也应该能够
to like have written my book during his
喜欢在已经写我的书， 他的
interview yes and I don't think it's
采访是的 ，我认为 不是
just communication problems as far as
至于刚刚沟通问题
you know don't think it can do it and
你知道不认为它可以做到这一点
other Buddhists say when they watch the
其他佛教徒在观看时说
water and that there is some beauty that
水， 有一些 美
there's some depth and being sure that
有一些深度和被确认
they can communicate with communication
他们可以与沟通沟通
that's also very important here because
这也是非常重要的因为
I mean look part of my job is being a
我的意思是看我工作的一部分是 作为 一个
teacher and I know some very intelligent
老师，我知道一些非常聪明的人
professors even who just have a better
教授甚至只是有更好的
hard time communicating they come up
他们很难沟通起来
with all these brilliant ideas but but
这些才华横溢的想法，但但
to communicate with somebody else you
和别人 沟通 你
have to also be able to simulate their
也必须 能够模拟其
own mind yes and pettite build well
自己的想法是的，而且 pettite很好
enough and understand model of their
足够了解他们的模特
mind that you can say things that they
记住， 你可以说出 他们的 事情
will understand and that's quite
会理解，这是相当的
difficult and that's why today it's so
困难， 这就是今天的原因
frustrating if you have a computer that
如果你有一台计算机就会感到沮丧
makes some cancer diagnosis and you ask
做一些癌症诊断， 你问
it well why are you saying I should have
它为什么你说我应该有
a surgery if it and if they don't know
一个手术，如果它和如果他们不知道
can only reply or I was trained on five
只能回复 或我接受过五次训练
terabytes of data and this is my
数TB的数据，这 是我的
diagnosis boop boop beep beep yeah I
诊断boop boop beep beep 呀我
didn't doesn't really instill a lot of
没有真正灌输不了多少
confidence right right so I think we
信心对，所以我想我们
have a lot of work do one on
做了很多工作
communication there so what kind of what
沟通有那么什么样的 东西
kind of I think you're doing a little
那种 我认为 你正在做的一 点点
bit work and explainable eh uh yeah what
有点工作和解释 呃，是的，是什么
do you think are the most promising
你认为最有前途吗？
avenues is it mostly about sort of the
途径 主要是关于
Alexa problem of natural language
Alexa自然语言的问题
processing of being able to actually use
处理能够实际使用
human interpretable methods of
人类可解释的方法
communication so being able to talk to a
沟通，所以能够 与一个人 交谈
system and talk back to you or is there
系统并 与您 交谈 或在那里
some more fundamental problems to be
一些更基本的问题
solved I think it's all of above human
解决了我认为这完全是 人类 之上的
the natural language processing is
自然语言处理是
obviously important but they're also
显然很重要，但他们也是
more nerdy
更讨厌
fundamental problems like if you if you
基本问题，如果你，如果你
take you play chess
带你下棋
mmm I have to give this Paris key when
嗯，我必须给这个巴黎钥匙
did you learn Russian nobody watching
你学习俄罗斯没人看吗？
papyrus key I talk after the back more
纸莎草纸 钥匙我 后面 说话 更多
people can you teach yourself Russian to
人们可以 你 教自己 俄文
Tao what amalgam of bills of sim through
陶渊明通过什么类似的法案
dinner
晚餐
Wow but I would see languages do you
哇，但我会看到你的语言
know
知道
wow that's really impressive I've had
哇， 我 真的给人留下了深刻的印象
some contact base but my point was if
一些联系基地， 但我的观点是，如果
you play chess but you have you looked
你下国际象棋，但你有你看
at the alpha zero games there are the
在阿尔法零场那里比赛 是
actual games now just checking out some
实际游戏现在只是查看 一些
of them are just mind-blowing really
其中 真的很 令人兴奋
beautiful and if you ask how did it do
很漂亮 ，如果你 问它是怎么做的
that
那
you got that talk to them is hassabis I
你明白我的 谈话对他们来说是hassabis我
know others from beef mine all they will
他们会认识牛肉矿的其他人
ultimately be able to give you is big
最终能够 给你的是大事
tables of numbers matrices that define
定义的数字矩阵表
the neural networking and you can stare
神经网络，你可以凝视
at these know people's numbers till your
在这些 知道人的数字， 直到你的
face turned blue and it's you know I can
脸色变成蓝色，你知道我可以
understand much about why it made that
了解它为何如此成功
move and even if you have a natural
移动，即使你有自然
language processing that can tell you in
可以告诉你的语言处理
human language about all five seven
关于所有五个人的语言
points to eight still not gonna really
指向八个仍然不会真的
help so I think think there's a whole
帮助所以我认为有一个整体
spectrum of a fun challenge they're
他们是一个有趣的挑战的光谱
involved in and taking a computation
参与并进行计算
that does intelligent things and
做聪明的事情
transforming me into something equally
把我变成平等的东西
good equally intelligent but it's more
同样聪明，但更多
understandable and I think that's really
可以理解，我认为这是真的
valuable because I think as we put
很有价值，因为我认为我们提出的
machines in charge of evermore
机器永远负责
infrastructure in our world the power
我们世界的基础设施的力量
grid the trading on the stock market
电网股票交易
weapons systems and so on
武器系统等
it's absolutely crucial that we can
我们绝对至关重要
trust these a is a do or I want and
相信这是 一个或 我 想要的
trust really comes from understanding
信任真的来自理解
all right in a very fundamental way and
好的，非常 基本的方式 和
that's why I'm that's why I'm working on
这就是为什么我就是为什么我正在 努力的原因
this because I think the more if we're
这是因为我觉得如果我们的话就越多
gonna have some hope of ensuring that
会有一些希望确保这一点
machines have adopted our goals and that
机器都采用了我们的目标和
they're gonna retain them that kind of
他们会保留他们的那种
trust and
信任和
thank you needs to be based on things
谢谢你需要基于事物
you can actually understand preferably
你最好能理解
even make it perfectly to improve
甚至使其 完全 改善
theorems on even with a self-driving car
甚至还有一辆自动驾驶汽车的定理
right if someone just tells you it's
对，如果有人告诉你的话
been trained on tons of data and I never
我接受过大量数据培训， 而且 从未
crashed it's it's less reassuring than
坠毁它不如说 让人放心
if someone actually has a proof maybe
如果有人确实有证据可能
it's a computer verified proof but still
这是计算机验证的证据，但仍然
it says that under no circumstances is
它说在任何 情况下都不 是
this car just gonna swerve into oncoming
这辆车只会转向迎面而来
traffic and that kind of information
交通和那种信息
helps will build trust and build the
帮助 将建立信任 并建立 信任
alignment the alignment of goals the at
对齐目标的对齐方式
least awareness that your goals your
至少意识到你的目标是你的
values are aligned and I think even a
价值观是一致的 ，我认为甚至 是一个
very short term if you look at her you
如果你看着她就很短暂
know that today right this absolutely
知道今天这是 绝对的
pathetic state of cybersecurity that we
我们可疑的网络安全状况
have when it's or is it three billion
什么时候或者它是30亿
yahoo accounts which are packed almost
几乎包装好的雅虎帐户
every American's credit card and so on
每个 美国人的 信用卡等
you know it's why is this happening it's
你知道这就是 为什么会发生这种情况
ultimately happening because we have
最终发生，因为我们有
software took nobody fully understood
软件没有人完全理解
how it worked that's why the bugs hadn't
它是如何工作的 ，这就是bug没有的原因
been found right now and I think AI can
现在被发现了， 我想 AI可以
be used very effectively for offense for
非常 有效地用于进攻
hacking but it can also be used for
黑客但它也可以用于
defense know hopefully automating
防守 知道希望自动化
verifiability and creating is systems
可验证性和创造 是系统
that are built in different
这是建立在不同的
so you can actually prove things about
所以你可以真正证明一切
them right and it's it's important
他们是对的，这很重要
so speaking of software that nobody
所以说到没有人的软件
understands how it works of course a
了解它的工作原理 当然是一个
bunch of people asked by your paper
一堆人问你的论文
about your thoughts of why does deep and
关于你的为什么 深深 的思念 和
cheap learning work so well that's the
便宜的学习工作很好，这就是
paper but what what are your thoughts on
纸， 但你的想法是什么
deep learning these kind of simplified
深入学习这些 简化
models of our own brains have been able
我们自己的大脑模型已经能够
to do some successful perception work
做一些成功的感知工作
pattern recognition work and now with
模式识别工作，现在用
alpha zero and so on do some some clever
alpha 零等等 做一些聪明的事
things what are your thoughts about the
你对此有什么看法？
promise limitations of this piece great
承诺这件作品的局限性很大
I think there are a number of very
我觉得有很多
important insights very important
重要的见解非常重要
lessons we can already draw from these
我们已经可以从中吸取教训
kind of successes one of them is when
其中一个成功就是什么时候成功
you look at the human brain you see it's
你看着你看到它的 人 脑
very complicated a tenth of eleven
十分十分十分复杂
neurons and there are all these
神经元， 还有所有这些
different kinds of neurons and
不同种类的神经元和
yadda-yadda and there's been a long
yadda-yadda 已经很久了
debate about whether the fact that we
辩论是否 我们这个事实
have dozens of different kinds is
有几十种不同的是
actually necessary for intelligence
实际上需要智力
which a now I think quite convincingly
现在 我 觉得这很 令人信服
answer that question no it's enough to
回答这个问题， 这还不够
have just one kind if you look under the
有只有一种，如果你看一下下
hood of alpha zero there's only one kind
alpha零的引擎盖只有一种
of neuron and it's ridiculously simple a
神经元和它的荒谬简单a
simple mathematical thing so it's it's
简单的数学事物就是这样
not the it's just like in physics it's
不是 它就像物理学 一样
not the D if you have a gas with waves
如果 你有波浪的气体，不是D.
in it it's not the detailed nature of
在它里面，它不是详细的性质
the molecule the matter it's the
这个问题就是分子
collective behavior or somehow it
集体 行为 或某种方式
similarly it's it's it's this
同样地，它就是这样
higher-level structure of the network
更高层次的网络结构
that matters not that you have twenty
重要的不是你 有二十个
guys I think whom our brain is such a
伙计们， 我认为 我们的大脑就是这样的人
complicated mess because it wasn't
复杂的混乱，因为它不是
devolved just to be intelligent it was
只是为了变得聪明而已
evolved to also be self assembling right
演变成自组装权利
and self repairing right and
和自我修复的权利和
evolutionarily attainable matches and so
进化上可达到的 匹配等等
on yeah so I think it's pretty my my
是的所以 我认为这是 我的
hunch is that we're gonna understand how
预感是我们 要 理解的
to build a GI before we fully understand
在我们完全理解之前建立地理标志
how our brains work just like we we
我们的大脑如何像我们一样工作
understood how to build flying machines
了解如何建造飞行器
long before we were able to build a
早 在我们能够建立一个
mechanical work bird yes are you going
机械工作鸟是 你 要去
names you're given that the example
你给出了这个例子的名字
exactly of mechanical birds and
正是 机械鸟和
airplanes
飞机
yeah my plans do a pretty good job of
是的我的计划做 了 很好的 工作
flying without really mimicking bird
飞行没有 真正模仿鸟
flight and even now after 100 is 100
飞行， 甚至现在100后是100
years later did you see the TED talk
多年以后你看到了TED演讲
with a mr. mechanical bird you mentioned
先生你 提到的 机械鸟
it's amazing but even after that right
这太棒了，但即使在那之后也是如此
we still don't fly in mechanical birds
我们仍然不会飞机械鸟
because it turned out the way we came up
因为它证明了我们的出现方式
with but simpler and it's better for our
但更简单， 对 我们 来说更好
purposes and I think it might be the
目的，我认为它可能是
same there that's one lesson and another
那是同一课和另一课
lesson it is one what did when our paper
教训是 一个 在 我们的论文 做了 什么
was about
是关于
well first we wife is a physicist
首先，我们的妻子是物理学家
thought it was fascinating how there is
认为这是令人着迷的 还有 如何
a very closed mathematical relationship
一个非常封闭的数学关系
actually between our artificial neural
实际上我们的人工 神经
networks and a lot of things that we've
网络和我们做过的很多事情
studied for in physics go by nerdy names
研究了在物理去 了俗气的名字
like the renormalization group equation
像重整化群方程一样
and napoleons and yada yada yada and
和拿破仑和亚达亚达亚达和
when you look a little more closely at
当 你仔细 观察时
this you have you at first there was a
这个你一开始就有 一个
well there's something crazy here that
那里有一些疯狂的东西
doesn't make sense because we know that
因为我们知道这一点， 所以没有意义
if you even want to build a super simple
如果你甚至想建立一个 超级简单的
neural network with hell that part cat
神秘网络 与地狱 那部分猫
pictures and dog pictures right that you
照片和狗图片对你而言
can do that very very well now but if
现在可以做得非常好但是如果
you think about it a little bit you
你考虑一下你
convince yourself it must be impossible
说服自己这一定是不可能的
because if I have one megapixel even if
因为如果我有 一百万像素 ，即使
each pixel is just black or white
每个像素只是黑色或白色
there's 2 to the power 1 million
有2个功率100万
possible images which is way more than
可能的图像比 的方式 更
there are atoms in our universe right so
我们宇宙中 有原子 就是这样
in order to and then for each one of
为了，然后为每一个
those I have to assign a number which is
那些我必须指定一个数字
the probability that it's a dog right so
这是一个 正确的 狗 这样 的 概率
an arbitrary function of images is a
图像的任意功能 是
list of more numbers than there are
列出的数字比那里多
atoms in our universe so clearly I can't
我们宇宙中的原子如此清楚，我不能
store that under the hood of my my GPU
存储在我的GPU的引擎盖下
or maybe my computer yet somehow works
或者 我的电脑还能以某种方式工作
so what does that mean well it means
那么 这意味着 什么 呢？
that the out of all of the problems that
那 就是出了所有的问题
you could all try to solve with a neural
你们都可以尝试用神经来解决
network
网络
almost all of them are impossible to
几乎所有这些都是不可能 的
solve with a reasonably sized one but
解决一个合理的大小但是
then what we should show it in our paper
然后我们应该 在论文中 展示 它
was was that they the fraks the kind of
是他们 的那种破碎的那种
problems the fraction of all the
问题的 所有 分数
problems that you could possibly
你可能 会遇到的问题
pose that there that we actually care
摆在那里我们真正关心的
about given the laws of physics is also
关于给定物理定律也是如此
an infinitesimally tiny little part and
一个无限小的小部分
amazingly they're basically the same
令人惊讶的是，它们基本相同
part yeah it's almost such that our
部分是的，这几乎是我们的
world was created for I mean they kind
创造世界是因为他们善良
of come together yeah but you could say
走到一起 是的， 但你可以说
maybe where the world created the world
也许是世界创造世界的地方
that the world was created for us but I
世界是 为我们而 创造的 ，但我
have a more modest interpretation which
有一个更温和的解释
is that instead evolution in downest but
在downest，与其进化 ，但
neural networks precisely for that
精确的神经网络
reason because this particular
因为 这个特别的 原因
architecture as opposed to the one in
建筑而不是建筑
your laptop is very very well adapted
你的笔记本电脑非常适应
solving the kind of problems of nature
解决自然问题
kept presenting it our ancestors will
我们的祖先会继续呈现它
read so it makes sense that why do we
阅读所以我们为什么这样做是有道理的
have a brain in the first place it's to
有脑在它的 第一个地方
be able to make predictions about the
能够 做出关于。的预测
future mm-hm and so on so if we had a
未来 mm-hm等等，如果我们有一个
sucky system which could never solve it
sucky 系统永远无法解决它
wouldn't have a logic so but it's so
没有逻辑，但事实如此
this is this is a I think you're very
这是 我觉得你很好
beautiful fact yeah we also we also
美丽的事实是的我们也是
realize that there's there that we
意识到 我们就在 那里
they've been it's been earlier work on
他们一直都是早期的工作
on why deeper networks are good but we
为什么更深的网络是好的，但我们
were able to show an additional cool
能够表现出额外的酷感
fact there which is that them even
事实就是他们甚至
incredibly simple problems like suppose
非常简单的问题，比如假设
I gave you it I found the numbers and
我给了 你，我找到了数字和
asked you to multiply them together in
请你 到它们相乘
re you can write it's the few lines of
再次 ，你可以写 它的几 行
code boom done trivial if you just try
如果你只是尝试，代码繁荣完成琐碎
to do that with a neural network that
用神经网络做到这 一点
has only one single hidden layer in it
只有一个隐藏层
you can do it but you're gonna need two
你可以做到，但你需要 两个
to the power a thousand neurons and to
一千个神经元 的力量
multiply a thousand numbers which is
乘千号码是
again more neurons than their atoms in
再次更多的神经元比他们的原子
our universe okay that's nothing but if
我们的宇宙没关系，只有 如果
you're allowed if you love yourself
如果你爱自己，你就被允许了
make it a deep network with many layers
使它成为一个有很多层的深层网络
you only need four thousand neurons it's
你只需要4000 元 它
perfectly feasible so that's really
完全可行， 所以这是真的
interesting there yeah yeah so on
有意思，是的，是的，等等
another architecture type I mean you
另一种架构类型我的意思是你
mentioned Schrodinger's equation and
提到了薛定谔方程和
what what are your thoughts about
你有什么想法？
quantum computing and the role of this
量子计算 和这个的作用
kind of computational unit in creating
创造中的一种计算单位
an intelligent system in some Hollywood
一些好莱坞的智能系统
movies that are a lot mentioned my name
很多提到我名字的电影
you don't want to spoil them
你不想破坏他们
the
该
the NAD is building a quantum computer
NAD正在建造量子 计算机
list yes because the word quantum sounds
列出是 因为量子声音这个词
cool and so it's right mines first of
冷静， 所以它是正确的矿山 第一
all I think we don't need quantum
我认为我们不需要 量子
computers they build a GI I suspect your
他们建立一个地理标志的计算机我怀疑你的
brain is not quantum computer and then
然后，大脑不是量子计算机
they found sense so you don't even wrote
他们找到了感觉所以你甚至没有写过
a paper about that what many years ago
关于该文件是许多年前
would excite Chocula the decoherence
会激发Chocula的退相干
so-called B coherence time that how long
所谓的 B连贯时间 是多久
it takes until the quantum computer
直到量子计算机才需要
nosov what your neurons are doing gets
nosov你的神经元正在做什么
erased mm-hmm why just random noise from
擦除mm-hmm为什么只是随机噪音
the environment and then it's about 10
环境，然后它是大约 10
to the minus 21 seconds so as cool as it
到了零下21秒，所以很酷
would be to have a quantum computer in
将 有一个量子计算机
my head I don't think that fast
我的脑袋我不认为那么快
yeah on the other hand there are very
是的， 另一方面有非常
cool things you could do with quantum
你可以用 量子 做的很酷的事情
computers though I think we'll be able
计算机虽然 我认为我们能够
to do soon when we get big what bigger
当我们变得更大更大的时候做很快的事情
ones that might actually help machine
那些可能真正帮助机器的
learning do even better than the brain
学习比大脑更好
mm-hmm though for example one this is
mm-hmm虽然例如 这是一个
moonshot but hey you know learning is
moonshot 但嘿，你知道学习是
very much same thing is search mm-hmm if
非常相同的事情是搜索 mm-hmm if
you have if you try to train a neural
如果你试图训练神经，你就有
network to get really learn to do
网络要真正 学会做
something really well you'd have some
你会有 一些 非常好的东西
lost function you have some you have a
失去了功能你有一些你有
bunch of knobs you can turn represented
一堆旋钮， 你 可以转向代表
by a bunch of numbers and you're trying
通过一堆数字 ，你正在尝试
to tweak them so that it become as good
调整它们以使它变得一样好
as possible at this thing so if you
尽可能在 这件事上，如果你
think of a landscape with some Valley
想到一些 山谷的风景
where each dimension of the landscape
景观的每个维度
corresponds to some number you can
对应一些数字你可以
change you're trying to find the minimum
改变你试图 找出最小
and it's well-known that if you have a
众所周知， 如果你有一个
very high dimensional landscape
非常高的维度景观
complicated things super hard to find
复杂的事情超级难找
the minimum later quantum mechanics is
最小的后期量子力学是
amazingly good at this right if I want
如果我想的话，非常擅长这个权利
to know what's the lowest energy state
知道什么是最低能量 状态
this water can possibly have incredibly
这水可能会令人难以置信
hard to compute but we can but nature
很难计算， 但我们可以，但自然
will happily figure this out for you if
如果 将愉快地 算出来给你
you just cool it down and make you very
你只需冷静下来 ， 让 你 变得 非常
very cold if you put a ball somewhere
如果你 把球放在某个地方，我会 很冷
it'll roll down to its minimum and this
它会滚下来到 最小 ，这
happens metaphorically
隐喻地发生了
and the energy landscape too and quantum
和能量景观也是量子的
mechanics even used as a mode some
机械师甚至用作一种模式
clever tricks which today is machine
聪明的技巧，今天是机器
learning systems don't like if you're
学习系统 不喜欢你
trying to find the minimum and you get
试图找到最低限度，你得到
stuck in a little local minima here in
卡在 这里的 一个小 地方 极小
quantum mechanics you can actually
实际上你可以使用 量子力学
tunnel through the barrier and get
通过障碍隧道获得
unstuck in Yemen and that's really
在也门失业，这是真的
interesting yeah so it may be for
有趣，是的，所以它可能是
example it will one day use quantum
例如， 它有一天会使用量子
computers that help train neural
帮助训练神经的计算机
networks better that's really
网络更好，真的
interesting okay so as a component of
有趣的好，所以作为一个组成部分
kind of the learning process for example
例如，一种学习过程
yeah
是啊
let me ask sort of wrapping up here a
让我问一下这里的问题
little bit let me let me return to the
有点让我让 我回
questions of our human nature and and
我们的人性 和问题的问题
love as I mentioned so do you think you
喜欢我提到的所以你认为你
mentioned sort of a helper robot you can
你可以提到一种 辅助机器人
think of also personal robots do you
想想 你也是个人机器人
think the way we human beings fall in
想想我们人类陷入的方式
love and get connected to each other
爱和彼此联系
it's possible to achieve in an AI system
它可以在AI系统中实现
and human-level AI intelligence system
和人类人工智能系统
do you think we would ever see that kind
你认为我们会看到那种
of connection or you know in all this
连接或你知道这一切
discussion about solving complex goals
关于解决复杂目标的讨论
yeah as this kind of human social
是的，这种人类社会
connection do you think that's one of
连接你认为这是一个
the goals and the peaks and valleys that
目标 和波峰和波谷
with the raising sea levels that we'll
随着海平面上升我们将
be able to achieve or do you think
能够实现 或你是否想到
that's something that's ultimately or at
这是 最终或最终 的东西
least in the short term relative to
至少在短期 内相对于
other goals is not achievable I think
我认为其他目标是无法实现的
it's all possible and I mean in in
这一切都是可能的，我的意思是
recent there's that there's a very wide
最近有一个非常广泛的
range of guesses as you know among AI
AI中您所知道的猜测范围
researchers when we're gonna get a GI
研究人员，当我们要获得 地理标志时
some people you know like your friend
有些人就像你的朋友一样
Rodney Brooks says it's gonna be hundred
罗德尼布鲁 克斯说这将是 百人
hundreds of years least and then there
数百年来 最少，然后在那里
are many others I think it's gonna
还有很多其他我认为会有的
happen relative much sooner and recent
相对更快，最近发生
polls and be half or so or AI
民意调查，大约一半或AI
researchers think it's we're gonna get
研究人员认为我们会得到它
AGI within decades so if that happens of
几十年内的 AGI ，如果发生这种情况的话
course then I think these things are all
当然， 我 认为这些都是
possible but in terms of whether it will
可能， 但就是否会
happen I don't I think we shouldn't
发生我不认为 我们不应该
spend so much time asking what do we
花了很多时间问 我们是什么
think will happen in the future as if we
认为将来会 像我们一样发生
are just some sort of pathetic your
只是 某种可怜 你的
passive bystanders you know waiting for
你知道等待的被动旁观者
the future
未来
happen to us hey we're the ones creating
碰巧我们嘿，我们是创造者
this future right so we should be
这个未来的权利，所以我们应该 是
proactive about it and ask us of what
积极主动地， 并问我们什么
sort of future we would like to have
排序的未来，我们希望 有
happen that's right
发生这是正确的
trying to make it like that well what I
试图让它像我一样
prefer it to some sort of incredibly
它 喜欢某种 不可思议
boring zombie like future where there's
无聊的僵尸就像未来的地方一样
all these mechanical things happen it is
所有这些机械的事情都发生了
no fashion no emotion no experience
没有时尚 没有情感 没有经验
maybe even no I would of course much
也许甚至没有我当然会
rather prefer it if all the things that
如果所有 的东西 都相当喜欢它
we find that we value the most about
我们发现 我们最重视
humanity our subjective experience
人性我们的主观经验
passion inspiration you love you know if
你爱的激情灵感， 如果你知道
we can create a future where those are
我们可以创建一个未来，这些都是
those things do exist no I think
那些事情确实存在， 我想不到
ultimately it's not our universe giving
最终不是我们的宇宙 给予
meaning to us just us giving me the
对我们来说只是我们给我的意思
universe and if we build more advanced
宇宙，如果我们建立更高级
intelligence let's let's make sure we're
让我们确保我们的智慧
building in such a way that meaning
建筑就是这样的意义
these but it's part of it I want a lot
这些但是它的一部分我想要很多
of people that seriously study this
那些认真研究这个的人
problem and think of it from different
问题并从不同的角度思考
angles have trouble and the majority of
角度 有麻烦 和大多数
cases if they think through that happen
如果他们认真考虑 那种情况
you know are the ones that are not
你知道 那些 不是
beneficial to humanity right and so yeah
对 人类 有益 ，所以是的
so what what are your thoughts was an
那么 你的想法是 什么？
engine what's what should people you
引擎什么是你应该做的人
know I really don't like people to be
知道我真的不喜欢 的人 是
terrified
怔
you should what's a way for people to
你应该 为人们提供什么样的方式
think about it in a way that instead you
以某种方式思考它 而不是你
know we can solve it okay to make it
知道 我们可以解决它可以 做到这一点
better yeah no I don't think panicking
更好是啊不，我不认为恐慌
is gonna help in any way it's not
它会以任何方式帮助它不是
increase chances of things going well
事情进展顺利的可能性增加
either even if you are in a situation
即使你处于某种 状况
where there is a real threat
哪里有 真正的威胁
does it help if everybody just freaks
如果每个人都是怪胎，它会有所帮助吗？
out right no of course of course not I
当然不是，当然不是我
think yeah there are of course ways in
想是的，当然有方法
which things can go horribly wrong first
哪些事情可能先犯错误
of all it's important when we think
当我们思考时，这一切都很重要
about this thing this about the problems
关于这个问题， 关于这个问题
and risks that also remember how huge
和风险，也记得有多大
the upsides can be if we get it right I
如果我们做对了，我就可以取得优势
had everything everything we love about
拥有我们喜欢的一切
society and civilization of the product
社会和文明的产品
of intelligence so if we can amplify our
如果我们可以放大我们的智力
intelligence or machine intelligence and
智能或机器智能和
not anymore lose our loved one to what
不再失去我们所爱的人
we're told as an uncurable disease and
我们被告知是一种无法治愈的疾病
things like this of
事情是这样的
we should aspire to that so that can be
我们应该立志于 使能
a motivator I think reminding ourselves
我想提醒自己的动力
that the reason we try to solve problems
我们试图解决 问题 的原因
is not just because we're trying to
不只是 因为我们正在努力
avoid gloom but because we're trying to
避免忧郁，但因为我们正在努力
do something great but then in terms of
做一些伟大的事情，但在随后 的 条款
the risks I think um the entry the
我认为你进入 的风险
important question is to ask what can we
重要的问题是问我们能做什么
do today they will actually help yes how
今天他们实际上会帮助是的
come good may in it and dismissing the
可能会好起来并解雇
risk is not one of them you know it I
风险不是其中之一，你知道 我
find it quite funny often when I'm in on
当我进去时经常发现它很有趣
discussion panels about these things how
关于这些事情的讨论小组如何
the people who work for come for
为前来 工作的人
companies lobbies they're always like oh
公司游说他们总是喜欢哦
nothing to worry about nothing to worry
完全不用担心 没有什么好担心
about nothing to worry about
什么都不用担心
and the it's always all it's only
它始终只是它的全部
academics sometimes it's expressed
学者有时会表达出来
concerns that's not surprising at all if
如果担心的话就不足为奇了
you think about it Upton Sinclair
你想起了 厄普顿辛克莱
quipped right that it's hard to make
说得好，很难做到
your man believe in something when you
你的男人相信的东西 ，当 你
think some the fans are not believing in
想想一些 粉丝 不相信
it and and frankly we know a lot of
它和坦白地说 ，我们知道很多
these people in companies and that
这些人在公司和那
they're just as concerned as anyone else
他们和其他人一样关心
but if you're the CEO of a company
但如果你是公司的首席执行官
that's not something you want to go on
那 不是你 想要继续下去的 东西
record saying when you have silly
记录说你有傻话
journalists so we're gonna put a picture
记者所以我们要拍照
of a Terminator robot when they quote
他们引用的终结者机器人
you so so the issues are real and the
你这么问题是真实存在的
way I am the way I think about what the
这样我能我想什么 方式
issue is it is basically you know but
问题是它基本上你知道但是
the real choice we have is first of all
我们真正的选择 首先是
are we gonna stir this dismiss this the
我们是否会激起 这种解雇
risks and say well you know let's just
冒险并说得好，你知道 我们只是
go ahead and build machines that can do
继续 建造可以做到的机器
everything we can do better and cheaper
我们可以做得更好，更便宜的一切
you know let's just make yourselves
你知道让我们 自己做
obsolete as fast as possible or what
尽快过时或过时
could possibly go wrong right that's one
可能 会出错，就是那个
attitude the opposite attitude that I
态度与我相反的态度
think is to say is incredible potential
想想就是说是不可思议的潜力
you know let's think about what kind of
你知道让我们考虑一下什么样的
future we're really really excited about
未来我们真的非常兴奋
what are the shared goals that we can
我们可以共同的目标是什么
really aspire towards and then let's
真的很向往，然后让我们
think really hard on how about how we
觉得真的 很难 就如何 如何，我们
can actually get there as it's a start
实际上可以到达那里，因为这是一个开始
with it no don't start thinking about
有了它没有不 开始思考
the risk start thinking about the goals
风险 开始考虑目标
goals yeah and then when you do that
目标是啊，然后当你这样做
then you can think about the obstacles
那么你可以考虑一下障碍
you want to avoid well they often get
你想避免他们经常得到的
students coming in right here into my
学生们来到这里进入我的学生
office for career advising always ask
办公室 职业辅导总是问
them this very question where you
他们过这个问题， 你
want to be in the future man if all she
如果所有她想成为未来的 男人
can say is oh maybe I'll have cancer
可以说是 哦，也许我会患癌症
maybe I'll run over by a tortoise and
也许我会 被乌龟 碾过 来
obstacles instead of the bill he's just
障碍而不是他刚才的法案
gonna end up a hypochondriac paranoid
最终会形成一个忧郁的偏执狂
yeah whereas if she comes in and fire in
是的，如果她进来 并开火
her eyes and it's like I want to be
她的眼睛，它就像我 想成为
there and then we can talk about the
那时我们可以谈谈
obstacles and see how we can circumvent
障碍 ，看看我们如何规避
them that's I think a much much
他们认为我的想法非常多
healthier attitude and um that's really
更健康的态度 ，这是 真的
well plan and I I feel it's it's very
好的计划 和我觉得 它是 非常的
challenging to come up with a vision for
提出愿景的挑战
the future which we wish we are
我们 希望的未来
unequivocally excited about I'm not just
毫不含糊地兴奋我不仅仅是
talking now in the vague terms like yeah
现在用模糊的语言说话，比如说
let's cure cancer fine I'm talking about
让我们治好癌症我正在谈论
what kind of society do we want to
什么样的 社会 做我们 想要
create what do we want it to mean you
创造我们 想要它的意思
know to be human in the Age of AI in the
知道在人类的AI时代是人类
age of AGI so if we can have this
AGI的年龄， 所以如果我们能有 这个
conversation broad inclusive
对话广泛包容
conversation and gradually start
谈话并逐渐开始
converging towards some some future that
朝着某种未来趋同
with some direction at least that we
有一些方向，至少我们
want to steer towards right then then no
想转向正确然后没有
we'll be much more motivated to
我们会更有 动力
constructively take on the obstacles and
建设性地承担障碍和
I think if I had if I had the I think if
我想如果我有，如果我有，我想如果
you make if I try to wrap this up in a
如果我尝试将其包装成一个，你会做出来的
more sixteenth way I think I think we
更多的第十六种方式我认为我认为我们
can all agree already now that we should
现在我们 都应该同意
aspire to build AGI but doesn't
渴望建立AGI，但没有
overpower us but that empowers us and
压倒我们，但这使我们和
think of the many various ways that can
想到很多不同的方式，可以
do that whether that's from my side of
做到这一点无论是从 我 的 身边 的
the world of autonomous vehicles I I'm
我是自动驾驶汽车的世界
personally actually from the camp that
个人实际上来自营地
believes there's human level
相信有人的水平
intelligence is required to to achieve
需要智力才能实现
something like vehicles that would
类似的车辆 ， 将
actually be something we would enjoy
实际上是我们 会喜欢的东西
using and being part of so that's one
使用并成为 其中一员的一部分
example and certainly there's a lot of
例子，肯定有 很多
other types of robots in medicine and so
医学上的其他类型的机器人等
on so focusing on those and then and
因此专注于那些然后和
then coming up with the obstacles coming
然后想出的障碍来
up with the ways that that can go wrong
了的方式是可以 去错
and solving those one at a time and just
并且一次解决那些问题
because you can build an autonomous
因为 你可以建立一个自治的
vehicle even if you could build one that
车辆， 即使 你可以建造一个
would drive this finalize you know maybe
会推动这最终确定你知道 也许
there are some things in life that we
我们 生活中 有一些事情
would actually want to do ourselves
实际上我想自己做
that's right my
那是对的
like for example if you think of our
例如，如果你想到 我们的
society as a whole there's something
社会作为一个整体有一些东西
that we find very meaningful to do and
我们觉得这样做非常有意义
that doesn't mean we have to stop doing
这并不意味着我们必须 停止这样做
them just because machines can do them
他们只是因为机器可以做到这一点
better you know I'm not gonna stop
你 知道我不会停下来
playing tennis just the base of my build
打网球 只是我身材的基础
a tennis robot yeah beat me people are
一个网球机器人呀击败我的 人
still playing chess and even go yeah and
还在下棋，甚至去和耶和华
I in this in the very near term even
我在这很短期内甚至
some people are advocating basic income
有些人在倡导基本收入
replace jobs but if you if the
替换工作，但如果你，如果
government is gonna be willing to just
政府会 愿意 只
hand out cash to people for doing
把钱 交给人们 做
nothing then one should also seriously
什么也没有人应该认真对待
consider whether the government should
考虑政府是否应该
also just hire a lot more teachers and
也只是雇用了更多的老师 和
nurses and the kind of jobs which people
护士和那种工作 ，人们的
often find great fulfillment in doing
经常发现做得很好
right I get very tired of hearing
对， 我 厌倦了听力
politicians saying oh we can't afford
政治家说我们买不起哦
hiring more teachers but we're going to
雇用更多的老师，但我们会去
maybe have basic income if we can have
如果我们可以拥有，可能有基本收入
more serious research and thought into
更认真的研究和思考
what gives meaning to our lives and the
什么赋予了我们的生活和意义
jobs give so much more than income right
工作给予的收入远远超过收入
mm-hm and then think about in the future
嗯，再想想 在未来
well what are the role of the yeah what
什么是什么角色是什么
are the roles that we want to have
是我们想要的角色
people feeling empowered by machines and
让人感慨的机器 和 授权
I think sort of I come from the Russia
我想我有点来自俄罗斯
from the Soviet Union and I think for a
从苏联 ，我想了
lot of people in the 20th century going
很多人在20世纪前进
to the moon going to space was an
到月球去太空 是一个
inspiring thing I feel like the the the
鼓舞人心的事情，我觉得这样的
universe of the mind so AI understanding
宇宙的心灵让AI理解
creating intelligence is that for the
创造智慧是为了
21st century so it's really surprising
21世纪所以真的很 令人惊讶
and I've heard you mention this it's
我听说你提到这个了
really surprising to me both on the
对我来说 真的很惊讶
research funding side that it's not
研究资金方面，它不是
funded as greatly as it could be but
尽可能多地获得资助但是
most importantly on the politicians side
最重要的是在政客方面
that it's not part of the public
它不是公众的一部分
discourse except in the kilobots
话语除了公斤机器人
Terminator kind of view that people are
终结者有种观点
not yet I think perhaps excited by the
还没有我认为也许是兴奋的
possible positive future that we can
我们 可能的 积极未来
build together certainly should be
一定要一起建立
because politicians usually just focus
因为政治家通常只关注
on the next election cycle right the
在下一个选举周期 中
single most important thing I feel we
我认为最重要的一件事
humans have learned and the entire
人类已经学会了整个
history of science is there were the
科学史是有的
Masters of underestimation we
低估我们的大师
underestimated
低估
the science of our cosmos
我们 宇宙的科学
again and again realizing of everything
一次又一次地实现 一切
we thought existed was just a small part
我们认为存在只是一小部分
of something grander right planet solar
伟大的权利 行星太阳能
system the galaxy clusters of guises
系统银河系 的 伪装
universe so and we now know that we but
宇宙如此，我们现在知道， 我们可是
the future has just so much more
未来还有更多
potential than our ancestors could ever
比我们的祖先更有潜力
have dreamt of this cosmos well imagine
梦想这个宇宙很好想象
if all of Earth was completely devoid of
如果整个 地球完全没有
life except for Cambridge Massachusetts
生活除了剑桥马萨诸塞州
that would wouldn't it be kind of lame
那不会 有点蹩脚
if all we ever aspired to it to stay in
如果我们都渴望它留在那里
Cambridge Massachusetts forever and then
马萨诸塞州剑桥永远然后
go extinct in one week
在一周内灭绝
even though Earth was gonna continue on
即使地球将继续下去
for longer that that sort of attitude I
我的 那种 态度 更长久了
think we have now on the cosmic scale we
认为我们现在对 宇宙尺度 我们
can fluid life can flourish on earth not
流体生命可以在地球上蓬勃发展
foreign for four years but for billions
外国人 四年，但数十亿
of years yes I can even tell you about
年是 我甚至可以告诉 你
how to move it out of harm's way when
如何将它从 伤害的 方式 移开
its own Sun gets too hot and and then we
它自己的太阳太热，然后我们
have so much more resources out here
这里有更多的资源
which today yeah maybe there are a lot
今天 也许有很多
of other planets with bacteria or a cow
其他有细菌 或 牛的行星
like life on them but I most of this all
喜欢他们的生活，但 我最 重要的是
this opportunity seems as far as we can
这个机会似乎尽我们所能
fail to be largely dead like the Sahara
失败在 很大程度上是死像撒哈拉沙漠
Desert and yet we have the opportunity
沙漠，但我们有机会
but to help
但是要帮助
life flourish promise there are billions
生活蓬勃发展承诺有数十亿
of year and so like let's quit
一年 等等让我们退出
squabbling about when some little border
一些小边界争吵
should be drawn one-fifth one mile to
应该画 五分之一英里
the left to right and realize hey you
从左到右，实现嘿你
know we can do such incredible things
知道我们可以做出如此不可思议的 事情
yeah and that's I think why it's really
是的，我认为为什么这是真的
exciting that yeah you and others are
令人兴奋，是的，你和其他人
connected with some of the working la
一些工作 LA的连接
mosque is doing because he's literally
清真寺正在做，因为他确实是
going out into that space we're
走出去成的空间 我们
exploring our universe and it's
探索我们的宇宙，它是
wonderful that is exactly why Elon Musk
精彩，这正是伊隆马斯克的原因
is so it misunderstood right misconstrue
是如此误解了正确的误解
him is some kind of pessimistic dooms
他是某种悲观的厄运
there the reason he cares so much about
这 就是他如此关心 的 原因
the I safety is because he more than
我的安全是因为他超过
almost anyone else appreciates these
几乎所有人都欣赏这些
amazing opportunities they will squander
他们将浪费的惊人机会
if we wipe out out here on earth
如果我们在地球上消灭
and we're not just gonna wipe out the
而且我们不只是要消灭掉
next generation but all generations and
下一代， 但所有世代和
this incredible opportunity that's out
这个令人难以置信的机会
there that would be really a waste and
还有那才是真正的浪费 ，
AI for people who think that we better
对于认为我们更好的人来说，AI
to do without technology well let me
没有技术做好让我
just mention that if we don't improve
只要 提一下，如果我们不改进
our technology the question isn't
我们的技术问题不是
whether humanity is gonna go extinct
无论 人类 是会走向灭绝
question is just whether we're gonna get
问题是我们是否会得到
taken out by the next big asteroid or
由 下一个大的小行星取出或
the next supervolcano or something else
下一个超级火山或其他东西
dumb that we could easily prevent with
愚蠢， 我们可以很容易地防止
more tech right and if we want life to
更多的技术权利，如果我们想要的生活
flourish throughout the cosmos AI is the
在整个宇宙中蓬勃发展AI是
key to it as I mentioned a lot of detail
关键是，我提到了很多 细节
in my book right there even many of the
在我的书 里，甚至还有很多
most inspired sci-fi writers I feel have
最有灵感的科幻作家，我觉得有
totally underestimated the opportunities
完全低估了机会
for space travel especially to other
太空旅行尤其是其他旅行
galaxies because they weren't thinking
星系， 因为他们 没有思考
about the possibility of AGI which just
关于AGI的可能性 刚刚
makes it so much easier right yeah so
使得它容易得多 权呀等等
that goes to your view of AGI that
那就是你对AGI的看法
enables our progress that enables a
使我们的进步成为可能
better life so that's a beautiful that's
更好的生活，这是一个美丽的
a beautiful way to put it and then
一个美丽的方式 把它 再
something to strive for so max thank you
努力的事情，所以最大的谢谢你
so much thank you for your time today
非常感谢你今天的时间
it's been awesome thank you so much
它一直真棒 非常感谢你
thanks Super Bowls Rory yes
谢谢Super Bowls Rory是的
you
您